{"cards": [{"_id": "","answer": "A local area network (LAN) is a computer network within a small geographical area such as a home, school, computer laboratory, office building or group of buildings.\nA LAN is composed of inter-connected workstations and personal computers which are each capable of accessing and sharing data and devices, such as printers, scanners and data storage devices, anywhere on the LAN.\nLANs are characterized by higher communication and data transfer rates and the lack of any need for leased communication lines.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Local Area Network (LAN) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A network diagram is used in computer telecommunication to draw a graphical chart of a network.\nThis type of diagram is particularly useful for network engineers and designers in compiling detailed network documentation.\nGenerally, a network diagram usually consists of a network that is made up of interconnected groups or systems.\nThe scope of a simple network diagram can be either a single application, a family of applications or even an entire enterprise.\nThere are also other complicated network diagrams broadly designed to cover home networks, wireless networks, networking wirings, LAN networks, network topology, activity networks and network cabling.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Network Diagram mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Network science studies the links among diverse fields of sciences such as engineered, information and biological networks.\nFrom a simple peer-to-peer network to large, high-end networks like the World Wide Web, the common purpose of all network structures is to share network resources or information like files, folder, printers, scanners, etc.\nThe core feature of network sciences is to design common principles, algorithms and tools that can govern these network activities.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Network Science mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Network theory is an field of computer science and network sciences and is also part of graph theory (the study of graphs and mathematical structures).\nNetwork theory is often deployed to examine the method of characterizing and modeling complex networks.\nMany complex networks share some common features, such as scale-free degree distribution.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Network Theory mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Artificial intelligence (AI), also known as machine intelligence, is a branch of computer science that aims to imbue software with the ability to analyze its environment using either predetermined rules and search algorithms, or pattern recognizing machine learning models, and then make decisions based on those analyses.\nIn this way, AI attempts to mimic biological intelligence to allow the software application or system to act with varying degrees of autonomy, thereby reducing manual human intervention for a wide range of functions.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Artificial Intelligence (AI) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Data, in the context of computing, refers to distinct pieces of digital information.\nData is usually formatted in a specific way and can exist in a variety of forms, such as numbers, text, etc.\nWhen used in the context of transmission media, data refers to information in binary digital format.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Data mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Electronic data interchange (EDI) is the electronic transmission of structured data by agreed message standards from one computer system to another without human intervention.\nIt is a system for exchanging business documents with external entities.\nEDI refers to a family of standards and does not specify transmission methods, which are freely agreed upon by the trading partners.\nThe wide adoption of EDI in the business world facilitates efficiency and cost reduction.\nEDI is used in such diverse business-to-business relationships as:\nInterchanges between health care providers and insurers\nTravel and hotel bookings\nEducation\nSupply chain management\nAdministration\nTax reporting\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Electronic Data Interchange (EDI) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Charles Babbage was an English mathematician and inventor who is widely credited for coming up with the concept of a programmed computer.\nBabbage was born in 1791, a time when computer actually meant a person who computes manually.\nEducated as a mathematician, Babbage noticed - as have many others since - that larger operations could be broken down into simpler, smaller stages.\nHowever, whether it was a small calculation or a large one, human error would always be a risk.\nBabbage envisioned a machine with an input device, storage, a processor, a control unit and an output device, essentially a basic modern computer.\nThis machine would be able to handle the basic calculations, thus eliminating human error.\nAlthough never completed, Babbage's Analytical Engine would have run on punch cards containing programs that could be run in a loop, allowing it to carry out any calculations that the programmer could design for it.\nBabbage also did work in the field of cryptography, breaking Vigenere's autokey cipher.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Charles Babbage mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A watchdog timer (WDT) is an embedded timing device that automatically prompts corrective action upon system malfunction detection.\nIf software hangs or is lost, a WDT resets the system microcontroller via a 16-bit counter.\nComputers lacking embedded WDTs often require installed WDT expansion cards.\n A WDT is also known as a computer operating properly (COP) timer.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": " Definition - What does Watchdog Timer (WDT) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computer-aided manufacturing (CAM) is an application technology that uses computer software and machinery to facilitate and automate manufacturing processes.\nCAM is the successor of computer-aided engineering (CAE) and is often used in tandem with computer-aided design (CAD).\nIn addition to materials requirements, modern CAM systems include real-time controls and robotics.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer-Aided Manufacturing (CAM) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computer networking is an engineering discipline that aims to study and analyze the communication process among various computing devices or computer systems that are linked, or networked, together to exchange information and share resources.\nComputer networking depends on the theoretical application and practical implementation of fields like computer engineering, computer sciences, information technology and telecommunication.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer Networking mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A computer network is a broad term for one of the biggest technological advances in computer science over the last 40 years.\nThe basic definition of a computer network is that a computer network connects parts of a distributed architecture, whether those parts are made up of hardware, or virtual or logical resources.\nNetworks are commonly categorized based on their characteristics.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer Network mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computer engineering refers to the study that integrates electronic engineering with computer sciences to design and develop computer systems and other technological devices.\nComputer engineering professionals have expertise in a variety of diverse areas such as software design, electronic engineering and integrating software and hardware.\nComputer engineering allows professionals to engage in a number of areas such as analyzing and designing anything from simple microprocessors to highly featured circuits, software design, and operating system development.\nComputer engineering is not limited to operating computer systems but is aimed at creating a broad way to design more comprehensive technological solutions.\nAlso known as computer system engineering.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer Engineering mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Integer overflow is the result of an attempt by a CPU to arithmetically generate a number larger than what can fit in the devoted memory storage space.\nArithmetic operations always have the potential of returning unexpected values, which may cause an error that forces the whole program to shut down.\nFor this reason, most programmers prefer to perform mathematical operations inside an exception frame, which returns an exception in the case of integer overflow instead.\nInteger overflow is also known as arithmetic overflow.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Integer Overflow mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Information processing refers to the manipulation of digitized information by computers and other digital electronic equipment, known collectively as information technology (IT).\nInformation processing systems include business software, operating systems, computers, networks and mainframes.\nWhenever data needs to be transferred or operated upon in some way, this is referred to as information processing.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Information Processing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Statistical mean is a certain kind of mathematical average that's very useful in computer science, and in machine learning in particular.\nSimply speaking, the statistical mean is an arithmetic mean process, in that it adds up all numbers in a data set, and then divides the total by the number of data points.\nThat's simple and straightforward, and so the arithmetic mean or statistical mean has been widely used throughout the modern era and into the age of computer programming.\nHere, we can differentiate the statistical mean from two other types of means that make up a group of three statistical methods called the Pythagorean means.\nThe other two means are called harmonic and geometric means.\nAll three of these can be useful in machine learning and new kinds of artificial intelligence algorithm engineering.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Statistical Mean mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Alphanumeric refers to a character set with alphabetic characters (A-Z) and numerals (0-9).\nOther characters also may be included in an alphanumeric character set.\nAlphanumeric data is useful for storing text and website addresses.\nAlphanumeric is also known as alphameric.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Alphanumeric mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Abstraction is the act of representing essential features without including the background details or explanations.\nIn the computer science and software engineering domain, the abstraction principle is used to reduce complexity and allow efficient design and implementation of complex software systems.\nSome areas of software design and implementation where the abstraction principle is applied include programming languages (mainly in object-oriented programming languages), specification languages, control abstraction, data abstraction and the architecture of software systems.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Abstraction mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "R/390 is an expansion card used in an IBM RS/6000 mainframe server.\nAll the server's configurations, as well as its complete systems, are called R/390.\nThe R/390 system is an IBM mainframe system designed to run on a personal computer.\nThe R/390 servers were marketed as development environments that provided an economical approach for companies moving their legacy applications from old mainframe systems to a new operating environment.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does R/390 mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A wide area network (WAN) is a network that exists over a large-scale geographical area.\nA WAN connects different smaller networks, including local area networks (LANs) and metro area networks (MANs).\nThis ensures that computers and users in one location can communicate with computers and users in other locations.\nWAN implementation can be done either with the help of the public transmission system or a private network.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Wide Area Network (WAN) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Functional dependency is a relationship that exists when one attribute uniquely determines another attribute.\nIf R is a relation with attributes X and Y, a functional dependency between the attributes is represented as X-&gt;Y, which specifies Y is functionally dependent on X.\nHere X is a determinant set and Y is a dependent attribute.\nEach value of X is associated with precisely one Y value.\nFunctional dependency in a database serves as a constraint between two sets of attributes.\nDefining functional dependency is an important part of relational database design and contributes to aspect normalization.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Functional Dependency mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An Internet bot is a specific kind of technology that interfaces with the global Internet to provide different kinds of automations.\nLike the Internet itself, Internet bots have been evolving through the years.\nSome of the most basic types of Internet bots are very common on the web.\nMany of them accomplish simple tasks, and some are named after what they do \u2014 \u201cweb scrapers\u201d is an excellent example.\nCompanies utilize these Internet bots to automatically collect data, or to send data, or do other routine tasks.\nSome of the more sophisticated Internet bots such as spambots will be let loose to provide spam comments all over various Wordpress blogs and other web venues, to the consternation of webmasters in general.\nThe concept of the Internet bots also applies to cybersecurity, and has been a major part of the cybersecurity world for years.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Internet Bot mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Peripheral Component Interconnect Bus (PCI bus) connects the CPU and expansion boards such as modem cards, network cards and sound cards.\nThese expansion boards are normally plugged into expansion slots on the motherboard.\nThe PCI local bus is the general standard for a PC expansion bus, having replaced the Video Electronics Standards Association (VESA) local bus and the Industry Standard Architecture (ISA) bus.\nPCI has largely been replaced by USB.\nThis term is also known as conventional PCI or simply PCI.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Peripheral Component Interconnect Bus (PCI Bus) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Alan Turing was an English mathematician and pioneer in the fields of cryptology and computer science.\nHis most famous contribution to the field of computing was the Universal Turing Machine.\nThis was a conceptual computer, which could calculate any algorithm using an infinite tape and a mechanical unit capable of reading, erasing and writing results upon the tape.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Alan Turing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computer science is the study of both computer hardware and software design.\nIt encompasses both the study of theoretical algorithms and the practical problems involved in implementing them through computer hardware and software.\nThe study of computer science has many branches, including artificial intelligence, software engineering, programming and computer graphics.\nThe need for computer science as a discipline has grown as computers become more integrated into our day-to-day lives and technology continues to advance.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer Science mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Merit Network Inc.\nis a nonprofit organization that provides computer networking and related services to educational, governmental, health care and nonprofit organizations in the state of Michigan.\nMerit's network is the longest-running regional computer network in the United States.\nIt evolved alongside ARPANET, and eventually became a cornerstone of the National Science Foundation Network (NSFNet), which served as a backbone for the modern Internet.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Merit Network mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Stochastic refers to data which has a random probability that may be analyzed via statistics.\nAlthough individual events cannot be predicted, analyzing the distribution of random stochastic variables may result in a pattern.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Stochastic mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The National Science Foundation (SF) is a U.\nS.\nfederal government agency that promotes and supports research and education in math, science, engineering and computer technology.\nThe NSF is the major source of federal funds for computer science research.\nInitial research into networking was conducted by the NSF, which would eventually lead to the development of the Internet.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does National Science Foundation (NSF) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A data scientist is an individual, organization or application that performs statistical analysis, data mining and retrieval processes on a large amount of data to identify trends, figures and other relevant information.\nA data scientist performs data analysis on data stored in data warehouses or data centers to solve a variety of business problems, optimize performance and gather business intelligence.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Data Scientist mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A benchmark computer is a computer used to provide a specific calculation of how fast a certain computing task can be accomplished with specific hardware.\nBenchmarking, a broader process of using actual hardware to calculate computing speed, can apply to figuring out CPU clock rates, processor performance, or operating system and software application agility.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Benchmark Computer mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A system unit is the part of a computer that houses the primary devices that perform operations and produce results for complex calculations.\nIt includes the motherboard, CPU, RAM and other components, as well as the case in which these devices are housed.\nThis unit performs the majority of the functions that a computer is required to do.\nThe term system unit is generally used to differentiate between the computer itself and its peripheral devices, such as the keyboard, mouse and monitor.\nA system unit is also known as a chassis or a tower in layman's terms.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does System Unit mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Kryder\u2019s law is a term for an analysis of the density and capability of hard drive storage media over time.\nIt is seen as a correlate to Moore\u2019s law, a theory that holds that the number of transistors placed in an integrated circuit should double every two years, resulting in predictable progress in microprocessor speed.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Kryder's Law mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computing is the process of using computer technology to complete a given goal-oriented task.\nComputing may encompass the design and development of software and hardware systems for a broad range of purposes - often structuring, processing and managing any kind of information - to aid in the pursuit of scientific studies, making intelligent systems, and creating and using different media for entertainment and communication.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Nyquist\u2019s law is a formula which states that to accurately represent an analog signal in a digital format, two samples per cycle are sufficient.\nIn other words, the analog signal sampling rate must be at least two times the maximum analog frequency to extract all bandwidth information and accurately represent analog signals in a digital format.\nSampling rates that slightly exceed twice the suggested frequency level leads to imprecision in filters and other components used for analog to digital conversion.\nNyquist\u2019s law is also known as Nyquist\u2019s Theorem.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Nyquist's Law mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A real number is any positive or negative number available within the entire mathematical range of numbers.\nReal numbers include whole numbers, rational numbers, irrational numbers and virtually any type of number that is not an imaginary number or that can't be computed or processed logically.\n Real numbers have a significant importance in the field of computer science.\nComputers use some types of real numbers, specifically floating point numbers, which are used to store a wide range of numbers within a finite limit of decimal points, making them easier to compute.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Real Number mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Neuroinformatics refers to a research field that focuses on organizing neuroscience data through analytical tools and computational models.\nIt combines data across all scales and levels of neuroscience in order to understand the complex functions of the brain and work toward treatments for brain-related illness.\nNeuroinformatics involves the techniques and tools for acquiring, sharing, storing, publishing, analyzing, modeling, visualizing and simulating data.\nNeuroinformatics helps researchers to work together and share data across different facilities and different countries through the exchange of approaches and tools for integrating and analysing data.\nThis field makes it possible to integrate any type of data across various biological organization levels.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Neuroinformatics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A recursive function is a function in code that refers to itself for execution.\nRecursive functions can be simple or elaborate.\nThey allow for more efficient code writing, for instance, in the listing or compiling of sets of numbers, strings or other variables through a single reiterated process.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Recursive Function mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Peterson's algorithm is a concurrent programming algorithm developed by Gary L.\nPeterson in a 1981 paper.\nIt is known as a simple algorithm when compared to others.\nPeterson proved the algorithm using both the 2-process case and the N-process case.\nPeterson's algorithm is used for mutual exclusion and allows two processes to share a single-use resource without conflict.\nIt uses only shared memory for communication.\nPeterson's formula originally worked only with two processes, but has since been generalized for more than two.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Peterson's Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A mnemonic is a term, symbol or name used to define or specify a computing function.\nMnemonics are used in computing to provide users with a means to quickly access a function, service or process, bypassing the actual more lengthy method used to perform or achieve it.\nAssembly language also uses a mnemonic to represent machine operation, or opcode.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Mnemonic mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The A+ certification is a basic certification that demonstrates proficiency with computer hardware and operating systems (OS).\nIt is governed by nonprofit trade association CompTIA.\nThe A+ certification helps prove the recipient's proficiency with the use of computers and related devices.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does A+ Certification mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Nanophotonics refers to the use of light in nanoscale projects.\nThis field is associated with some specific breakthroughs in using light in new technologies, including silicon-based semiconductors, where nanophotonics improve speed and performance.\nNanophotonics is also known as nano-optics.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Nanophotonics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Binary code is the most simplistic form of data.\nIt is represented entirely by a binary system of digits consisting of a string of consecutive zeros and ones.\nBinary code is often associated with machine code in that binary sets can be combined to form raw code, which is interpreted by a computer or other piece of hardware.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Binary Code mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A binary file is a type of computer file that is used to store binary data.\nIt may contain any type of formatted or unformatted data encoded within binary format.\nIt is used directly by the computer and generally can't be read by a human.\nBinary files may also be called binaries.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Binary File mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An ARM processor is a specific type of computer processor designed according to a model developed by ARM Holdings PLC.\nThis processor design is described as a reduced instruction set computing (RISC) design, where a simplified central processing unit (CPU) design accommodates higher performance.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does ARM Processor mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The black-white bakery algorithm is an enhancement to Lamport\u2019s bakery algorithm that satisfies all the conditions of a mutual exclusive algorithm.\nThis algorithm preserves the original Lamport algorithm while using a finite number of atomic registers of bounded size and satisfies FIFO fairness.\nIt is also adaptive and satisfies local spinning.\nThe black-white bakery algorithm is designed to provide a software based solution to mutual exclusion.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Black-White Bakery Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Lamport\u2019s bakery algorithm is a computing algorithm that ensures efficient use of shared resources in a multithreaded environment.\nThis algorithm was conceived by Leslie Lamport and was inspired by the first-come-first-served, or first-in-first-out (FIFO), operational methodology of a bakery.\nLamport\u2019s bakery algorithm is a mutual exclusion algorithm that restricts two or more processes from accessing a resource simultaneously.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Lamport's Bakery Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "IBM PC is the brand name of the first popular commercial PC developed by the IBM Corporation.\nIn 1981, the IBM PC was launched with the model number IBM 5150 in an attempt to set an industry benchmark subsequent to the IBM 5100 and several other computers.\nThe IBM PC was also code named Acorn.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does IBM PC mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A tree topology is a type of network topology that includes at least three specific levels in a topology hierarchy.\nTree topologies are valued for their scalability and accessibility for troubleshooting.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Tree Topology mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Singularity refers to the emergence of super-intelligent machines with capabilities that cannot be predicted by humans.\nThis theoretical idea sounds like science fiction, but the increasing speed of computing power has led many experts to believe that it will eventually transform human life to something that would not be recognizable today.\nAccording to science fiction writer Vernor Vinge, who popularized the term, the Singularity could occur as a result of artificial intelligence (AI), human biological enhancement or brain-computer interfaces.\nThe Singularity is also known as: \"The Technological Singularity.\n\"","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does The Singularity mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Ring topology refers to a specific kind of network setup in which devices are connected in a ring and pass information to or from each other according to their adjacent proximity in the ring structure.\nThis type of topology is highly efficient and handles heavier loads better than bus topology.\nA ring topology may also be called an active topology because messages are passed to each device in the ring.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Ring Topology mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A micron is a unit of measurement that is often used to measure the size of processors, microprocessors and their components.\nIt is 1/1,000th of a millimeter or 1/25th of a thousandth of an inch.\nMicron is short for micrometer.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Micron mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Code management in the process of handling changes to computer code.\nAs opposed to general project management, code management deals in the precise management of code modules or collections of lines of code in order to support changes or particular goals such as maintenance or debugging.\nCode management is sometimes called source code management when handling code involves looking behind an interface to the actual programming that is hidden beneath it.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Code Management mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A zettaflop (ZFlop) is a unit of measurement for computer processing power.\nIt refers to the floating point operations per second (FLOPS) capacity of a processor, where one ZFlop represents 1021 FLOPS.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Zettaflop mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Loose coupling describes a coupling technique in which two or more hardware and software components are attached or linked together to provide two services that are not dependent on one another.\nThis term is used to describe the degree and intent of interconnected but non-dependent components within an information system.\nLoose coupling is also known as low or weak coupling.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Loose Coupling mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computational complexity is a computer science concept that focuses on the amount of computing resources needed for particular kinds of tasks.\nIn computational complexity theory, researchers assess the kinds of resources that will be needed for a given type or class of task in order to classify different kinds of tasks into various levels of complexity.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computational Complexity mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Tight coupling is a coupling technique in which hardware and software components are highly dependent on each other.\nIt is used to refer to the state/intent of interconnectivity between two or more computing instances in an integrated system.\nTight coupling is also known as high coupling and strong coupling.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Tight Coupling mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A two-tier architecture is a software architecture in which a presentation layer or interface runs on a client, and a data layer or data structure gets stored on a server.\nSeparating these two components into different locations represents a two-tier architecture, as opposed to a single-tier architecture.\nOther kinds of multi-tier architectures add additional layers in distributed software design.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Two-Tier Architecture mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A tabular database, as the name implies is a database that is structured in a tabular form.\nIt arranges data elements in vertical columns and horizontal rows.\nEach cell is formed by the intersection of a column and row.\nEach row and column is uniquely numbered to make it orderly and efficient.\nThis type of database has a virtually infinite range for mass data storage.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Tabular Database mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computing, an independent variable is any variable that changes its value under a process, program, event, or any computing-specific interaction.\nIt is used in computer programming to be assigned to a variable value, entity or process, or to calculate the value of a dependent variable.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Independent Variable mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computing, a dependent variable is any variable whose value, output or functioning depends on two or more independent variables.\nA dependent variable is used in computer programming to represent a value, process, function or entity within the programming paradigm/context/architecture.\nA dependent variable is also known as an outcome variable.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Dependent Variable mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A character set refers to the composite number of different characters that are being used and supported by a computer software and hardware.\nIt consists of codes, bit pattern or natural numbers used in defining some particular character.\nA character set may also be referred to as character map, charset or character code.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Character Set mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A computer system is a basic, complete and functional computer, including all the hardware and software required to make it functional for a user.\nIt should have the ability to receive user input, process data, and with the processed data, create information for storage and/or output.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer System mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A source code analysis tool analyzes source code or compiled code.\nTypically, these kinds of resources look for security flaws or issues within code.\nVarious providers offer source code analysis tools for software markets.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Source Code Analysis Tool mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An entity is any singular, identifiable and separate object.\nIt refers to individuals, organizations, systems, bits of data or even distinct system components that are considered significant in and of themselves.\nThe term is used in a number of programming languages/concepts, database management, systems design and other arenas.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Entity mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Daisy chain routers are routers that have been connected in a cascading manner, in sequence or a ring, either to extend the number of computers that can be connected via wires to the local area network or to add wireless capabilities to a network.\nThe idea is to connect one router as an extension of a main router, either as a port extender or a signal extender.\nThe term \"daisy chain\" comes from the garland created by connecting daisies to each other to form a chain.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Daisy Chain Routers mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Data center cooling refers to the collective equipment, tools, techniques and processes that ensure an ideal operating temperature within a data center facility.\nProper data center cooling ensures that the data center is supplied with enough cooling and ventilation necessary to keep all devices and equipment within the desired temperature range.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Data Center Cooling mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Load testing software is a type of software that tests a software or web application by implementing user load on it.\nIt mimics user load/requests on software by implementing a large quantity of simultaneous connection or access requests on the tested software or applications.\nLoad testing software is also known as stress testing software.\n ","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Load Testing Software mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A fingerprint scanner is a type of technology that identifies and authenticates the fingerprints of an individual in order to grant or deny access to a computer system or a physical facility.\nIt is a type of biometric security technology that utilizes the combination of hardware and software techniques to identify the fingerprint scans of an individual.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fingerprint Scanner mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Network traffic analysis is the process of recording, reviewing and analyzing network traffic for the purpose of performance, security and/or general network operations and management.\nIt is the process of using manual and automated techniques to review granular-level detail and statistics within network traffic.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Network Traffic Analysis mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A computer-aided system engineering (CASE) tool is a resource for achieving high-quality and error-free software.\nThroughout the early years of software design, the tech community developed this term to talk about the idea of using computer programs to help human developers create new systems or applications.\n ","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer-Aided System Engineering Tool (CASE Tool) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "End Of File or EOF is a specific designation for a file marker that indicates the end of a file or data set.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does End Of File (EOF) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A linear function is a mathematical expression which, when graphed, will form a straight line.\nA linear function is a simple function usually composed of constants and simple variables without exponents as in the example, y = mx + b.\nThis type of function is popular in economics because of its simplicity and ease in handling.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Linear Function mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Boolean expression is one that conforms to one of two given Boolean results, commonly characterized as true or false.\n These expressions and operators are a core part of computer science and programming languages.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Boolean Expression mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Bohr bug is an error, flaw or failure that appears under consistent and quantifiable conditions.\nThe Bohr bug is named after the atomic model developed by Danish physicist Niels Bohr.\nThere is a rough similarity, in that like the atomic model, the Bohr bug conforms to certain kinds of logic, in this case, programming logic.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Bohr Bug mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A circular reference in computer programming is a situation in which two values reference each other.\nThis type of reference can be extremely problematic if two functions or values depend on one another for definition.\nThis term is used in the IT world much like it is in general language to refer to when one thing references another and vice versa.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Circular Reference mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Footprinting is a term not exclusive to computer science, but often used in information technology to refer to efforts to find out about computer systems and their networks, or footprints.\nAlthough footprinting can be done for legitimate purposes, the term is often linked to hacking and cyber attacks.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": " Definition - What does Footprinting mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Fog computing is a term for an alternative to cloud computing that puts some kinds of transactions and resources at the edge of a network, rather than establishing channels for cloud storage and utilization.\nProponents of fog computing argue that it can reduce the need for bandwidth by not sending every bit of information over cloud channels, and instead aggregating it at certain access points, such as routers.\nThis allows for a more strategic compilation of data that may not be needed in cloud storage right away, if at all.\nBy using this kind of distributed strategy, project managers can lower costs and improve efficiencies.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fog Computing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An expression is a particular concept in computer science in which a number of variables or constants, and operators and functions, are put together in a single statement that is acted on by a particular programming language.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Expression mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Layer 1 is the first layer of the Open Systems Interconnect (OSI) Model.\nLayer 1 consists of the various networking hardware and transmission technologies being employed by networks.\nThis layer is the first and serves as the foundation, the fundamental layer underneath the logical data structures of other higher level network functions.\nThis is considered as the most complex layer simply because of all the different hardware combinations there is possible.\nLayer 1 is also known as the Physical Layer.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Layer 1 mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A changelog is a record of changes to a software project or other technology product.\nThis type of record has its own format for various types of projects, but is generally useful in showing when and why changes were made, and who made them.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Changelog mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Programming logic is a fundamental construct that's applied to computer science in a variety of comprehensive ways.\nProgramming logic involves logical operations on hard data that works according to logical principles and quantifiable results.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Programming Logic mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Distributed denial of service (DDoS) prevention refers to the collective tools, processes and methodologies that enable a network, information system or IT environment to be protected from DDoS attacks and intrusions.\nIt is a security and hardening technique that ensures that optimal or normal computing operations continue even under a DDoS attack.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Distributed Denial of Service Prevention (DDoS Prevention) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "'Trusted computing\u2019 (TC) is the concept that technologies have built-in processes to revolve basic security problems and user challenges.\nIt is also a term used by a trade group called the Trusted Computing Group (TCG) that helps to set standards for devices and technologies.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Trusted Computing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Dotted decimal notation is a system of presenting numbers that is a little different from the common conventions in arithmetic as it is taught in schools.\nSpecifically, dotted decimal notation is used in various IT contexts, including in Internet Protocol addresses.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Dotted Decimal Notation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In IT, the word \"session\" is a reference to a certain time frame for communication between two devices, two systems or two parts of a system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Session mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Boolean logic is a type of computer science originally developed by mathematician George Boole in the mid-1800s.\nIt supports a great deal of algorithmic programming and the emergence of computing functionality approaching artificial intelligence (AI).\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Boolean Logic mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Antikythera mechanism is an ancient mechanical analog computer designed specifically to predict and calculate the positions and movements of stars and planets.\nIt is among the oldest forms of computer, and was designed by Greeks in 86 BC.\nIt was lost some years after its development, but was recovered in early 1900.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Antikythera Mechanism mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Accessibility testing is the process of testing software, hardware, a website or virtually any IT component's ease of use for individuals with certain disabilities.\nIt is done to ensure to that any new component can easily be accessible by physically disabled individuals despite any respective handicaps.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Accessibility Testing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A multiprocessor is a computer system with two or more central processing units (CPUs), with each one sharing the common main memory as well as the peripherals.\nThis helps in simultaneous processing of programs.\nThe key objective of using a multiprocessor is to boost the system\u2019s execution speed, with other objectives being fault tolerance and application matching.\nA good illustration of a multiprocessor is a single central tower attached to two computer systems.\nA multiprocessor is regarded as a means to improve computing speeds, performance and cost-effectiveness, as well as to provide enhanced availability and reliability.\n ","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Multiprocessor mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Turing machine is a theoretical machine that manipulates symbols on a tape strip, based on a table of rules.\nEven though the Turing machine is simple, it can be tailored to replicate the logic associated with any computer algorithm.\nIt is also particularly useful for describing the CPU functions within a computer.\nAlan Turing invented the Turing machine in 1936, and he referred to it as an \"a-machine\" or automatic machine.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Turing Machine mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Data protection as a service (DPaaS) is a cloud-based or web-delivered service for protecting data assets.\nCompanies can utilize this type of service to enhance network security and to build better security for data in transit and data at rest.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Data Protection as a Service (DPaaS) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Informatics is the study of the behavior and structure of any system that generates, stores, processes and then presents information; it is basically the science of information.\nThe field takes into consideration the interaction between the information systems and the user, as well as the construction of the interfaces between the two, such as the user interface.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Informatics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Point-to-point encryption (P2PE) is a process of securely encrypting a signal or transacted data through a designated \"tunnel.\n\" This is most often applied to credit card information encrypted from the merchant point-of-sale (POS) entry to the final credit card processing point, often maintained by a third party.\nThe principle of P2PE can protect sensitive data in many different ways.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Point-to-Point Encryption (P2PE) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Integration architecture is a software architecture that facilitates the integration of multiple IT components.\nThis architecture changes with the advances in cross-platform utility and other development paradigms for new kinds of digital operations.\n ","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Integration Architecture mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "I/O spikes are extreme changes in network demands that can cause certain impacts on distributed computing systems.\nThis general term can be used to describe the different kinds of network or system impacts that may be problematic for planners and IT professionals.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does I/O Spikes mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Bedroom programming refers to the different types of amateur programming, in contrast to a highly controlled or corporate programming process.\n Definitions of \"bedroom programming\" can vary quite a bit.\nSome define bedroom programming as amateur programming that is not done for profit.\nIn other definitions, the term simply refers to the projects of programmers who are \"going it alone\" rather than working directly in a corporate office environment.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Bedroom Programming mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Medium-scale integration is the process of embedding hundreds of transistors in one integrated circuit or microchip.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Medium-Scale Integration (MSI) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A nanotube is a nanoscale material that has a tube-like structure.\nNanotube structures have many applications in the general field of nanotechnology, which is a relatively recent field with much potential, as well as some significant liabilities.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Nanotube mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "IO bootstorms are problems that arise when many individual users simultaneously boot up a common operating system.\nThis usually happens in systems that use a virtual desktop infrastructure environment, where each system has many individual users logging onto the same operating system built into a virtual network.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does I/O Bootstorms mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Hot add refers to the ability to dynamically add hardware, virtual or physical, to a running system without downtime.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hot Add mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A vCPU (virtual CPU) represents a portion or share of a physical CPU that is assigned to a virtual machine (VM).\nA vCPU is also known as a virtual processor.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does vCPU mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A terminal emulator is a software application that replicates the functionalities of classic computer terminals.\nThese terminals consisted of a monitor and a keyboard, and were used mainly to access another computer, such as a minicomputer or a mainframe.\nThe terminal emulator performs the same functionality in software.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Terminal Emulator mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Round robin scheduling (RRS) is a job-scheduling algorithm that is considered to be very fair, as it uses time slices that are assigned to each process in the queue or line.\nEach process is then allowed to use the CPU for a given amount of time, and if it does not finish within the allotted time, it is preempted and then moved at the back of the line so that the next process in line is able to use the CPU for the same amount of time.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Round Robin Scheduling (RRS) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In programming languages, an else statement is an alternative statement that is executed if the result of a previous test condition evaluates to false.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Else Statement mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Open-source architecture is a concept that combines the advances in design and technologies with the practices and ideas from open-source projects to help reframe an architectural design as a collective and collaborative endeavor.\nThe focus of open-source architecture is on the potential interactions of a structure with its social, physical and other contexts based on the people involved rather than on a top-down solution or a linear process.\nIt transforms the architecture for adaptive use and to an inclusive and transparent architecture.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Open-Source Architecture mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Nanolithography is a branch of nanotechnology and the name of the process for imprinting, writing or etching patterns in a microscopic level in order to create incredibly small structures.\nThis process is typically used for creating smaller and faster electronic devices such as micro/nanochips and processors.\nNanolithography is mainly used in various sectors of technology from electronic to biomedical.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Nanolithography mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Context-aware security refers to the use of different types of context information to enhance security practices or the capabilities of security applications.\nIn context-aware security, security researchers gather different types of data, including device locations, time of day, device types and other indicators, that may have some bearing on security performance.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Context-Aware Security mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Cloud elasticity refers to the ability of a cloud service to provide on-demand offerings, nimbly switching resources when demand goes up or down.\nIt is often an immediate reaction to clients dropping or adding services in real time.\nCloud elasticity is also known as rapid elasticity.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cloud Elasticity mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "C++ is a versatile programming language developed by Bjarne Stroustrup in 1979.\nBased on the C programming language, C++ added some object-oriented features to the former to support modern uses.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does C++ mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Tail recursion is the act of calling a recursive function at the end of a particular code module rather than in the middle.\nA function is recursive if it calls itself.\nThis programming concept is often useful for self-referencing functions and plays a major role in programming languages such as LISP.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Tail Recursion mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The tilde (~) is a character in the standard ASCII character set that is provided on a conventional computer keyboard and is used in both writing and computer programming.\nIt corresponds to ASCII code 126.\nThe tilde is also sometimes known as the twiddle.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Tilde (~) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A CPU ready queue is a queue that handles jobs or tasks for eventual scheduling with a processor.\nThe term is often used in virtualization setups, where IT professionals try to determine whether resources have been allocated well and whether different components of the system can work efficiently.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does CPU Ready Queue mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Workload placement is a term that has developed in reference to managing resources in hardware virtualization systems.\nIt involves the assignment of workloads in such a way that VM efficiency is optimized.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Workload Placement mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The traveling salesman problem (TSP) is a popular mathematics problem that asks for the most efficient trajectory possible given a set of points and distances that must all be visited.\nIn computer science, the problem can be applied to the most efficient route for data to travel between various nodes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Traveling Salesman Problem (TSP) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "CPU congestion is a type of bottleneck caused by an excessively high demand on the capabilities of a processor in a given network or system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does CPU Congestion mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "CPU contention is an event wherein individual CPU components and machines in a virtualized hardware system wait too long for their turn at processing.\nIn such a system, resources (e.\ng.\n, CPU, memory, etc.\n) are distributed between different virtual machines (VMs).\nAs different processing resources are assigned to different machines, the schedulers in the system order the input/output and other tasks.\nThe processing of these tasks is delayed when the machines assigned to them are experiencing a CPU contention.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does CPU Contention mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "CPU wait is a somewhat broad and nuanced term for the amount of time that a task has to wait to access CPU resources.\nThis term is popularly used in virtualized environments, where multiple virtual machines compete for processor resources.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does CPU Wait mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "CPU ready is a type of processing statistic that represents the amount of time that a component is ready to process a job but is waiting on a scheduler for access to a physical processor.\nIt is used in virtualization setups and other kinds of IT hardware architectures.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does CPU Ready mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A CPU bottleneck is a situation wherein too many demands on a physical CPU degrade system performance or make the system run slower.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does CPU Bottleneck mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Virtual memory (vMem) is memory that is allocated by virtualization systems.\nHere, virtual memory addresses are translated to physical memory addresses within hardware setups.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does vMem mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A zombie VM is a virtual machine that is not functioning properly in a software environment, but continues to operate, sucking up resources and providing no value.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Zombie VM mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Hallway usability testing is a technique and a principle in usability testing wherein random individuals are used to test software products and interfaces.\nThis is in contrast to choosing individuals based on particular skills they may have.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hallway Usability Testing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Usability testing is a simple and central idea in IT that involves testing software products, interfaces or technologies on end users.\nUsability testing is important to develop strategies for finding out how systems work practically when they are delivered to customers.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Usability Testing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Remote usability testing is a type of testing wherein designers and engineers do research on a user interface by testing it on end users.\nIn this type of testing, planners or testers use remote access technology to test interfaces on users \"in their natural environments.\n\"\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Remote Usability Testing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Concept testing is an IT-related marketing term that refers to efforts to evaluate a concept and its reception by a target audience.\nConcept testing takes many forms such as surveys, focus groups and other kinds of planning tools that help a business understand how much a consumer audience likes its ideas.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Concept Testing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Time complexity is a concept in computer science that deals with the quantification of the amount of time taken by a set of code or algorithm to process or run as a function of the amount of input.\nIn other words, time complexity is essentially efficiency, or how long a program function takes to process a given input.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Time Complexity mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Type inference is the automatic deduction of the data types of specific expressions in a programming language, usually done at compile time.\nIt involves analyzing a program and then inferring the different types of some or all expressions in that program so that the programmer does not need to explicitly input and define data types every time variables are used in the program.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Type Inference mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An open system, in the context of computing, is a computer system that combines portability and interoperability, and makes use of open software standards.\nIt typically refers to a computer system that is interoperable between different vendors and standards, allowing for modularity so that hardware and software need not be attached to a single vendor or platform.\nBefore the popularity of the Windows OS and the PC, open systems used to refer to computer systems with Unix-like operating systems that accepted any modules or programs from any third party that used the same standard, as opposed to that era's closed systems such as IBM computers.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Open System mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Quicksort is a popular sorting algorithm that is often faster in practice compared to other sorting algorithms.\nIt utilizes a divide-and-conquer strategy to quickly sort data items by dividing a large array into two smaller arrays.\nIt was developed by Charles Antony Richard Hoare (commonly known as C.\nA.\nR.\nHoare or Tony Hoare) in 1960 for a project on machine translation for the National Physical Laboratory.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Quicksort mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Supervisor mode is a mode of execution in a device in which all instructions, including privileged ones, can be performed by the processor.\nIt is thus capable of executing both input/output operations and privileged operations.\nThe operating system of a computer usually operates in this mode.\nSupervisor mode helps in preventing applications from corrupting the data of the operating system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Supervisor Mode mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Subject-oriented programming is an object-oriented approach in which different subsystems known as subjects are divided to create new subjects based on the composition expression.\nThe approach is a radical departure from the classical object-oriented approach, in which objects are defined based on their properties and methods.\nSubject-oriented programming is largely oriented toward dividing an object-oriented system into subjects.\nIt thus provides a compositional view of the application development.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Subject-Oriented Programming mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Tautology is a type of logic construct that can be applied in IT.\nIt refers to a redundant logic wherein a principle is restated or is evident in its expression.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Tautology mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A syllogism is a deductive reasoning construct wherein logical arguments follow from each other.\nIt can be used in different types of programming and in IT.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Syllogism mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Application workload demand is the demand placed on a system by an application.\nIT professionals use strategies such as workload tiering, workload balancing or workload management to anticipate and deal with application workload demand.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Application Workload Demand mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The term \"application container,\" which has several meanings in IT, has come to be used for a new type of technology that helps provide consistency and efficient design in the context of hardware virtualization.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Application Container mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Docker is an open platform that helps with the universal distribution of applications.\nIt has become a standard for certain types of container virtualization systems and has been adopted by various companies as a software container strategy.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Docker mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Three-schema architecture is an idea in relational database design that breaks a database down into three different categories according to its use and structure, and to the roles played by system administrators, designers and end users.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Three-Schema Architecture mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Cloud-based grid computing is commonly described as the use of computers connected to a public cloud system, in order to pursue large, collaborative tasks.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cloud-Based Grid Computing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Workload tiering is the practice of splitting up processing workloads for a given system.\nIt is often associated with tiered storage, where a system uses a variety of storage devices and storage destinations to split up data workload and storage tasking.\nThis can make processes more efficient, put less strain on particular servers or components, or otherwise level out system demands.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Workload Tiering mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Context delivery architecture (CoDA) is a broad-based term (commonly attributed to Gartner) that refers to the need for applications and modular parts of systems to be context aware or, in other words, to know as much as possible about a user context.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Context Delivery Architecture (CoDA) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Monte Carlo method is a mathematical procedure or algorithm in which random numbers are run through some model or simulation to observe the properties of large sets of results.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Monte Carlo Method mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Cloud performance management is the practice of assessing various metrics and benchmarks for cloud systems.\nIt is used to determine how well a cloud system is functioning and what improvements can be made to the system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cloud Performance Management mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Direct chip cooling is a modern method of cooling off a microprocessor chip by applying cooling solutions directly to the chip.\nThis can cool off a microprocessor faster than some other traditional technologies.\nDirect chip cooling is also known as direct-to-chip cooling.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Direct Chip Cooling mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Ladder logic is a programming language that creates and represents a program through ladder diagrams that are based on circuit diagrams.\nIt is mainly used in developing programs or software for programmable logic controllers (PLCs), which are used in industrial applications.\nThe language evolved from originally being a method for documenting the design and construction of relay racks used in manufacturing and process control, with each relay rack represented by a symbol on the ladder diagram that has connections to devices below them that look like vertical rails.\nThe relay symbols themselves look like rungs in a ladder.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Ladder Logic mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Perceptron is a machine learning algorithm that helps provide classified outcomes for computing.\nIt dates back to the 1950s and represents a fundamental example of how machine learning algorithms work to develop data.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Perceptron mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A showstopper bug is a hardware or software bug that causes an implementation to stop and become essentially useless.\nThis critical bug must be fixed for the development process to proceed further.\nThe term \"showstopper\" is used in an opposite manner to its classic theatrical usage, which describes something that is strikingly good.\nThe name itself specifies that every activity stops then and there, and, unless the bug is resolved, the process cannot go on.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": " Definition - What does Showstopper Bug mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In IT, a physical address refers to either a memory location, identified in the form of a binary number, or a media access control (MAC) address.\nA physical address is also known as a binary address or a real address.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Physical Address mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Heterogeneous system architecture (HSA) is a particular processor architecture that combines a central processing unit (CPU) and a graphics processing unit (GPU) in order to speed up processes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Heterogeneous System Architecture (HSA) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Capacity utilization is a business term that is sometimes applied to IT to mean the efficient use of resources.\nIndustry experts use the term \"capacity utilization rate\" to show how well existing resources are being used or at what percentage they are being drawn from.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Capacity Utilization mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Elastic multitenancy refers to the idea that a system can accommodate multiple client storage resources together (\"multitenant\") and offer on-demand changes within the system (\"elastic\").\nThe term is commonly used in modern cloud computing and network virtualization.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Elastic Multitenancy mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Versamodule Eurocard Bus (VMEbus) is a bus or computer data path device that can be integrated into different hardware systems.\nA VMEbus may be used for traffic control systems, weapons controls systems, robotic systems or other important hardware setups.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Versamodule Eurocard Bus (VMEbus) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A virtual address in memory is a pointer or marker for a memory space that an operating system allows a process to use.\nThe virtual address points to a location in primary storage that a process can use independently of other processes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Virtual Address (VA) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Virtual machine migration is the task of moving a virtual machine from one physical hardware environment to another.\nIt is part of managing hardware virtualization systems and is something that providers look at as they offer virtualization services.\nVirtual machine migration is also known as teleportation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Virtual Machine Migration (VM Migration) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An exclusive OR gate (XOR gate) is a digital logic gate that is implemented using transistors in order to act as an electronic switch used in implementing Boolean functions.\nIt is built by combining standard logic gates such as the common NAND and NOR gates in order to produce the more complex function of this gate.\nXOR produces a \"1\" output if the inputs are different and a \"0\" if all the inputs are the same value.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Exclusive OR Gate (XOR Gate) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Intelligent workload management (IWM) is a relatively new offshoot of the general principle of workload management, which involves distributing computing and input/output tasks across a complex network.\nWith IWM, new advancements allow for some types of automation and sophisticated workload handling for modern cloud, hybrid or multi-platform systems.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Intelligent Workload Management (IWM) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Static code analysis is a method of analyzing and evaluating search code without executing a program.\nStatic code analysis is part of what is called \"white box testing\" because, unlike in black box testing, the source code is available to the testers.\nMany types of software testing involve static code analysis, where developers and other parties look for bugs or otherwise analyze the code for a software program.\nStatic code analysis is also known as static program analysis.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Static Code Analysis mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science, the state of a program is defined as its condition regarding stored inputs.\nThe term \"state\" here is used similarly to how it is used in science \u2014 whereas the state of an object, for instance, as a gas, liquid or solid, shows its current physical makeup, the state of a computer program shows its current values or contents.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does State mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer programming, in Java specifically, transient is a keyword that is used to indicate that a variable should not be serialized.\nBy default, all variables in an object can be serialized and therefore become persistent, but if a specific variable does not require persistence for any reason, the transient keyword can be used to mark that variable so that it is not serialized when the code is compiled.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Transient mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Forward compatible is the ability of an IT system to be compatible with or to support a similar version of itself in the future.\nUnlike backward compatibility, forward compatibility ensures the integration of or interoperability support for newer versions of an IT system with existing ones.\nForward compatible is also known as upward compatible, future-time compatible or newer-version compatible.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Forward Compatible mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Nyquist frequency is a type of sampling frequency that uses signal processing that is defined as \u201chalf of the rate\u201d of a discrete signal processing system.\nIt is the highest frequency that can be coded for a particular sampling rate so that the signal can be reconstructed.\nThe Nyquist frequency is also known as the folding frequency.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Nyquist Frequency mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Real-time computing (RTC) is a term for computing practices that have specific time constraints.\nReal-time computing has to be done in a time frame that is relatively imperceptible to the user.\nBy contrast, other types of computing can be done on a delayed basis, for instance, where information is aggregated, kept and stored for later use.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Real-Time Computing (RTC) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A quine is a program that essentially outputs its own source code.\nAlthough this sounds simple, it can be quite complex because of the necessity of engineering a string that essentially prints itself on command.\nQuines are also known as self-replicating programs or self-copying programs.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Quine mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In the C programming language, scanf is a function that reads formatted data from stdin (i.\ne, the standard input stream, which is usually the keyboard, unless redirected) and then writes the results into the arguments given.\nThis function belongs to a family of functions that have the same functionality but differ only in their source of data.\nFor example, fscanf gets its input from a file stream, whereas sscanf gets its input from a string.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Scanf mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A quantum bit (qubit) is the smallest unit of quantum information, which is the quantum analog of the regular computer bit, used in the field of quantum computing.\nA quantum bit can exist in superposition, which means that it can exist in multiple states at once.\nCompared to a regular bit, which can exist in one of two states, 1 or 0, the quantum bit can exist as a 1, 0 or 1 and 0 at the same time.\nThis allows for very fast computing and the ability to do multitudes of calculations at once, theoretically.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Quantum Bit (Qubit) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A simulation is any research or development project where researchers or developers create a model of some authentic phenomenon.\nMany aspects of the natural world can be transformed into mathematical models, and using simulation allows IT systems to mimic the outcomes that happen in the natural world.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Simulation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A secure hash algorithm is actually a set of algorithms developed by the National Institutes of Standards and Technology (NIST) and other government and private parties.\nThese secure encryption or \"file check\" functions have arisen to meet some of the top cybersecurity challenges of the 21st century, as a number of public service groups work with federal government agencies to provide better online security standards for organizations and the public.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Secure Hash Algorithm (SHA) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The phrase \u201clines of code\u201d (LOC) is a metric generally used to evaluate a software program or codebase according to its size.\nIt is a general identifier taken by adding up the number of lines of code used to write a program.\nLOC is used in various ways to assess a project, and there is a debate on how effective this measurement is.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Lines Of Code (LOC) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Perceptual computing is a new and somewhat confusing term in IT.\nThe common definition of perceptual computing is a general advancement in technology where computers are better able to sense or analyze the environment around them and respond accordingly.\nPerceptual computing has a lot of potential to change the end-user interfaces through which humans interact with computers.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Perceptual Computing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Character encoding is the process of representing individual characters using a corresponding encoding system made up of other symbols and types of data.\nCharacter coding is used for many different purposes.\nCharacter encoding is also known as a character set or character map.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Character Encoding mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Predictive technology refers to a set of tools used for forecasting patterns in data while keeping in perspective the previous records/data.\nPredictive technology has been hugely implemented in marketing and business for forecasting demand and supply patterns.\nInitially the tools were introduced to study weather, the stock exchange, human behavior and socioeconomic activities.\nThe tools used are data mining, neural networks and system modeling and simulation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Predictive Technology mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Planck\u2019s Constant relates the energy of one photon (the smallest possible energy \u2018packet\u2019) of electromagnetic waves to the frequency of that wave, and is denoted by h.\nThe energy and frequency in the case of photon energy are directly proportional to each other, and hence Planck\u2019s constant is the constant of proportionality between them.\nPlanck\u2019s Constant is also known as the Plank Constant.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Planck's Constant mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In IT, pattern recognition is a branch of machine learning that emphasizes the recognition of data patterns or data regularities in a given scenario.\nIt is a subdivision of machine learning and it should not be confused with actual machine learning study.\nPattern recognition can be either \u201csupervised,\u201d where previously known patterns can be found in a given data, or \u201cunsupervised,\u201d where entirely new patterns are discovered.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Pattern Recognition mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An X-Y-Z matrix is a three-dimensional structure whereby the x-axis and y-axis denote the first two dimensions and the z-axis is the third dimension.\nIn a graphic image, the x denotes width, y denotes height and the z represents depth.\nAn X-Y-Z matrix is also known as a 3D matrix.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does X-Y-Z Matrix mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An X-Y matrix is a two-dimensional structure in which the x-axis denotes horizontal rows and y-axis denotes vertical columns.\nAn X-Y matrix is the most basic orientation for two-dimensional structures and spaces, such as graphs, screens of digital watches and calculators, led displays and two-dimensional graphical images.\nAn X-Y matrix is also known as a 2-D matrix.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does X-Y Matrix mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computing, word size refers to the maximum number of bits that a CPU can process at a time.\nA word is a fixed-sized piece of data which is dictated by the processor hardware architecture; fixed in a sense that it is the maximum size that the processor is always using, yet variable in the sense that word sizes vary amongst processor architectures, most notably because of generation and the state of technology.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Word Size mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science, a ternary tree is a type of tree data structure where each node can have up to three derivative nodes.\nThis is in contrast to a binary tree, where each node can have either one or two derivative nodes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Ternary Tree mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science and advanced mathematics, a ternary search is a search algorithm that uses a \"divide and conquer\" strategy to isolate a particular value.\nIt is similar to a binary search, but it divides the search data structure into three parts instead of two.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Ternary Search mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A function point (FP) is a component of software development which helps to approximate the cost of development early in the process.\nIt is a process which defines the required functions and their complexity in a piece of software in order to estimate the software's size and scope upon completion.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Function Point (FP) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Molecular electronics refers to the subdivision of nanotechnology and nanoelectronics that is responsible for electronics development and design using nano building blocks.\nAll modern fabrication of integrated circuits and electronic devices is possible due to advancements in molecular electronics.\nMolecular scale and material are two subdivisions of molecular electronics used in high-tech and artificial intelligence devices.\nMolecular electronics is also known as molecular-scale electronics, moletronics or molectronics.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Molecular Electronics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Protocol conversion is the process of translating the protocol of the sending device to a different protocol of another device so that compatibility and communication can be established.\nToday, heterogeneous networks exist in the communication world, and with lack of a uniform global standard for communication protocol, protocol mismatches can happen.\nThus it is important to have protocol conversions to mediate between incompatible protocol models.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Protocol Conversion mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A NOR gate is a type of logic gate that works on the principle of \u201cneither this nor that.\n\u201d This type of digital logic gate produces a high output only if two binary results are satisfied by a zero or low input.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does NOR Gate mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Subtyping is a notion in programming language theory where a subtype, which is a data type, is related to a supertype based on the notion of substitutability, where program elements such as functions and subroutines that are written for the supertype will still operate if given the subtype instead.\nSubtypes are an essential concept in object-oriented programming and are substitutable to supertypes and sometimes even have more stringent specifications than the supertype.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Subtyping mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "VMWare vRealize Automation is a proprietary VMWare tool for cloud provisioning and the automated delivery of personalized services in complex systems.\nVMWare vRealize Automation was formerly known as vCloud Automation Center.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does vRealize Automation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A menu is a graphical control element used in graphical user interfaces.\nIt lists options or commands for the user to select in order to execute the proper application function.\nMenus are a common feature of operating systems, software applications and Web-based applications.\nThey help in enhancing the visual presentation, organization and categorization of the contents presented to the user.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Menu mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Referential transparency is a property of a specific part of a program or a programming language, especially functional programming languages like Haskell and R.\nAn expression in a program is said to be referentially transparent if it can be replaced with its value and the resulting behavior is the same as before the change.\nThis means that the program's behavior is not changed whether the input used is a reference or an actual value that the reference is pointing to.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Referential Transparency mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A logarithm (LN) is a concept in mathematics that denotes the number of times a number has to be multiplied by itself in order to arrive at a specified value.\nIn mathematical terms, a logarithm of a number is the exponent that is used to raise another number, the base, in order to arrive at that number.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Logarithm (LN) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "System programming involves designing and writing computer programs that allow the computer hardware to interface with the programmer and the user, leading to the effective execution of application software on the computer system.\nTypical system programs include the operating system and firmware, programming tools such as compilers, assemblers, I/O routines, interpreters, scheduler, loaders and linkers as well as the runtime libraries of the computer programming languages.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does System Programming mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A knowledge-based system (KBS) is a computer system which generates and utilizes knowledge from different sources, data and information.\nThese systems aid in solving problems, especially complex ones, by utilizing artificial intelligence concepts.\nThese systems are mostly used in problem-solving procedures and to support human learning, decision making and actions.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Knowledge-Based System (KBS) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Hill climbing is a mathematical optimization heuristic method used for solving computationally challenging problems that have multiple solutions.\nIt is an iterative method belonging to the local search family which starts with a random solution and then iteratively improves that solution one element at a time until it arrives at a more or less optimized solution.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hill Climbing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Julian date, also commonly called as Julian day, refers to the number of days passed since the beginning of a self-created cycle of 7980 years.\nThis concept was introduced by Joseph Scaliger in 1538 and its importance is integral in number computation by determining the difference between two known dates.\nIt is largely used in computers and astronomy.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Julian Date mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A histogram is a type of graph that is widely used in mathematics, especially in statistics.\nThe histogram represents the frequency of occurrence of specific phenomena which lie within a specific range of values, which are arranged in consecutive and fixed intervals.\nThe frequency of the data occurrence is represented by a bar, hence it looks very much like a bar graph.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Histogram mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A hybrid computer is a type of computer that offers the functionalities of both a digital and an analog computer.\nIt is designed to include a working analog unit that is powerful for calculations, yet has a readily available digital memory.\nIn large industries and businesses, a hybrid computer can be used to incorporate logical operations as well as provide efficient processing of differential equations.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hybrid Computer mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The actor model is a computer science concept that uses \"actors\" as the fundamental agents of computing.\nActors take input, send output and perform functions.\nThey can also create other actors.\nThis type of model was involved in early packet switching, and, as a semantic model, it has helped to evolve different kinds of software programs.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Actor Model mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Prepend is a word that means to attach content as a prefix.\nIt is often used in different kinds of programming and in automated processes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Prepend mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer programming, the object class refers to a class created to group various objects which are instances of that class.\nClasses are code templates for creating objects.\nIn cases where objects need to be grouped in a certain way, an object class is the \"container\" for a set of objects built on these templates.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Object Class mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A fencepost error is a specific type of off-by-one error that has to do with unlikely or misunderstood algorithms for development.\nFencepost errors are also known as telegraph pole errors and lamppost errors.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fencepost Error mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Luhn formula is a simple checksum formula that is used in the validation of various identification numbers such as credit card numbers, social security numbers, IMEI numbers and many others.\nThe algorithm validates the number against an included check digit in the number itself, usually the last digit.\nThe Luhn formula is now in the public domain and is widely used in various industries and specified in ISO/IEC 7812-1.\nThe Luhn formula is also known as the Luhn algorithm, modulus 10 algorithm or mod 10 algorithm.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Luhn Formula mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Graph theory, in computer science and applied mathematics, refers to an extensive study of points and lines.\nA graph contains shapes whose dimensions are distinguished by their placement, as established by vertices and points.\nIn integrated circuits (ICs) and printed circuit boards (PCBs), graph theory plays an important role where complex layered microchips are interconnected to perform useful functions.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Graph Theory mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Information resource management (IRM) is a broad term in IT that refers to the management of records or information or data sets as a resource.\nThis can relate to either business or government goals and objectives.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Information Resource Management (IRM) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A garbage collector is a piece of software that performs automatic memory management.\nIts job is to free any unused memory and ensure that no memory is freed while it is still in use.\nSome languages such as Java and .\nNET languages feature automatic garbage collection, whereas others such as C/C++ require the programmer to manual manage memory.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Garbage Collector mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Five nines is the term used for describing the availability of a computer or a service at 99.\n999 percent of the time it is required.\nIn other words, the system or service is only unavailable for 5.\n39 minutes throughout the year for planned or unplanned downtime.\nFive nines is recommended and required for mission-critical requirements and for certain areas such as e-commerce.\nHowever, five nines availability has always been a challenge for a service or network and is often impossible to guarantee.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Five Nines mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A genetic algorithm is a heuristic search method used in artificial intelligence and computing.\nIt is used for finding optimized solutions to search problems based on the theory of natural selection and evolutionary biology.\nGenetic algorithms are excellent for searching through large and complex data sets.\nThey are considered capable of finding reasonable solutions to complex issues as they are highly capable of solving unconstrained and constrained optimization issues.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Genetic Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A full-text search is a comprehensive search method that compares every word of the search request against every word within the document or database.\nWeb search engines and document editing software make extensive use of the full-text search technique in functions for searching a text database stored on the Web or on the local drive of a computer; it lets the user find a word or phrase anywhere within the database or document.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Full-Text Search mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Apache Storm is an open-source Apache tool used to process unbound streams of data.\nProviding real-time data processing solutions, Storm provides a topology to control data transfers, which is a critical part of routing data where it needs to go for analytics and other operations.\nIt coordinates with other kinds of Apache tools such as database or scaling resources.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Apache Storm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The General Algebraic Modeling System (GAMS) is a computer system that models mathematical operations.\nIt is extremely useful in solving both linear and nonlinear types of equations, as well as various particular types of high-level problems.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does General Algebraic Modeling System (GAMS) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Garbage, in the context of computers, is used to refer to any unwanted or unused data occupying memory space.\nUnallocated memory must be free of garbage values before allocating them, as the presence of garbage values may cause security issues and exceptional conditions.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Garbage mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Fractals are complex patterns that are self-similar, and therefore exhibit similar patterns at every scale.\nFractals can be patterns or shapes that are non-regular and differ from traditional geometric shapes, but occur very commonly in nature, such as clouds, mountains, trees and snowflakes.\nThe most well-known illustration of fractals is the Mandelbrot set, which when magnified simply shows repetitions of the same pattern, making it hard to determine the level of magnification due to the recurring patterns.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fractal mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Fibonacci sequence is a sequence of numbers in which each successive number in the sequence is obtained by adding the two previous numbers in the sequence.\nThe sequence is named after the Italian mathematician Fibonacci.\nThe sequence starts with zero and one, and proceeds forth as 0, 1, 1, 2, 3, 5, 8, 13, 21, 34, 55 and so on.\nThe Fibonacci sequence is widely used in applications pertaining to mathematics, science, computers, art and nature.\nThe Fibonacci sequence is also known as the Fibonacci series or Fibonacci numbers.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fibonacci Sequence mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Flux is a common phenomenon throughout the natural world and has become a ubiquitous concept throughout physics and mathematics, and hence technology.\nFlux describes the flow of a physical property through space and is often coupled with a time variation.\nThere are two common usages or contexts for flux, each having solid mathematical frameworks \u2013 flux as a vector in the context of transport phenomena and flux as a scalar quantity in the context of electromagnetism.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Flux mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computing devices, an exclamation point is the punctuation mark provided in standard keyboards, smartphones and other devices.\nApart from the usage of indicating strong feelings while messaging or chatting, an exclamation point has a wide range of usage in computer science.\nIn most operating systems, exclamation points are used for indicating warnings, errors and precautionary steps or statements.\nAn exclamation point is also known as an exclamation mark or, in the context of computing, a bang.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Exclamation Point mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Endian refers to how the order of bytes in a multi-byte value is perceived or acted upon.\nIt is the system of ordering the individual elements in a digital word in a computer\u2019s memory as well as describing the order of transmission of byte data over a digital link.\nDigital words may be represented as little-endian or big-endian.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Endian mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Not a Number (NaN) represents an undefined number in floating-point operations.\nA Not a Number indicator may also be a sign that a variable that is supposed to be a numerical value has been corrupted by text characters or symbols.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Not a Number (NaN) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In IT, blocking can be used in many ways to talk about the prevention of some action or command, or the hiding of some visual element from an interface.\nWhen something is blocked, it does not function or \u201cgo through\u201d an interface.\nBlocking can be a user preference, or an essential part of a hardware and software system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Blocking mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A banana problem, in IT, describes an algorithm, piece of code or technology artifact that has vague delimiters or problems with definition or scope.\nA banana problem may be similar to a fencepost error, which is described as a \u201cproblem with the discrete equivalent of a boundary condition.\n\u201d\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Banana Problem mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A bug compatible piece of software is a piece of software that has bugs or glitches in common with a prior version of the software.\nThe idea is that a company has not improved the product to eliminate the bugs.\nBug compatible is also known as bug-for-bug compatible.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Bug Compatible mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Electromagnetic compatibility (EMC) is the ability of different electronic devices and components to work correctly even in the presence of other devices that emit electromagnetic waves.\nThis means that each piece of equipment emitting EM waves or disturbances must have it limited to a certain level and that each individual device must have adequate immunity to EM disturbances in the environment it is meant to function in.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Electromagnetic Compatibility (EMC) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Network optimization is technology used for improving network performance for a given environment.\nIt is considered an important component of effective information systems management.\nNetwork optimization plays an important role as information technology is growing at exponential rates with business users producing large volumes of data and thus consuming larger network bandwidths.\nIf proper network optimization is not in place, the continuous growth can add strain to the network architecture of the concerned environment or organization.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Network Optimization mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Fourier transform is a mathematical function that takes a time-based pattern as input and determines the overall cycle offset, rotation speed and strength for every possible cycle in the given pattern.\nThe Fourier transform is applied to waveforms which are basically a function of time, space or some other variable.\nThe Fourier transform decomposes a waveform into a sinusoid and thus provides another way to represent a waveform.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fourier Transform mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The word \u201ccuration\u201d in IT refers to those processes for selecting, maintaining and storing digital assets.\nIn general, this may refer to any type of digital asset including text, images, video, multimedia, or even other types of technology content, such as unformatted digital posts or rich media pieces, or small physical hardware items.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Curation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An attribute-value pair (AVP) is a fundamental representation of data in computer systems and its various applications.\nThe attribute-value pair is a good way of storing and modeling real-world data in a database.\nA good example of this is how personal data such as a name is stored, by using an attribute called \"first name\" followed by its value pair, which is the actual first name of the person.\nAn attribute-value pair is also known as a name-value pair, key-value pair or field-value pair.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Attribute-Value Pair (AVP) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A stemmer is an algorithm that operates on the principle of recognizing \u201cstem\u201d words embedded in other words.\nThese are helpful for lexical purposes, for example, in online dictionaries, for heuristics in file management, or anywhere else that semantic tools can help create order.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Stemmer mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A typographic hierarchy is a system that uses typography \u2013 the size, font and layout of different pieces of text \u2013 to create a hierarchical division that can show users where to look for specific kinds of information.\nIt is an organizing system for establishing order in a set of data.\nBy creating different sizes, shapes and blocks of text, developers can direct the user's eye to the information that an audience needs the most, or otherwise categorize that information visually for the audience.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Typographic Hierarchy mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Axiomatic semantics are semantic expressions of the relationships inherent in a piece of code.\nThese expressions can be helpful in describing how some piece of software works.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Axiomatic Semantics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The \u201csemantic gap\u201d as it is often referenced in IT is the difference between high-level programming sets in various computer languages, and the simple computing instructions that microprocessors work with in machine language.\nThis classic difference has compelled engineers and designers to look at different ways of mediating between high-level language and basic machine language.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Semantic Gap mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The angle bracket (&lt; or &gt;), which is also called an \u201cinequality sign\u201d\nfor its use in mathematics, is a kind of sideways caret that can be used to\ninclude tags or pieces of code.\nThis ASCII set of characters is common in web\ndesign and other types of coding projects.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Angle Bracket mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Breidbart Index is in index developed by Seth Breidbart\nfor identifying spam in newsgroups.\nUsers take advantage of the Breidbart Index\nto try to point out which types of posts should be eliminated as spam messages.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Breidbart Index mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Bignum is a tool for code representation for integers that\nare too large for the conventional integer declaration or value type in many\nmainstream programming languages.\nSince the value type integer in these\nlanguages only goes up to a value of 2,147,483,648 a bignum value type represents\nnumbers that are larger than that.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Bignum mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Cyber defense is a computer network defense mechanism which includes response to actions and critical infrastructure protection and information assurance for organizations, government entities and other possible networks.\nCyber defense focuses on preventing, detecting and providing timely responses to attacks or threats so that no infrastructure or information is tampered with.\nWith the growth in volume as well as complexity of cyber attacks, cyber defense is essential for most entities in order to protect sensitive information as well as to safeguard assets.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cyber Defense mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Conway's law is an aphorism in IT that posits the idea that \u201corganizations\nwhich design systems are constrained to produce designs which are copies of the\ncommunication structures of these organizations.\n\u201d This idea can be traced back\nto a programmer named Melvin Conway who developed this principle in the late\n1960s.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Conway's Law mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "\u201cConsidered harmful\u201d is a kind of insider IT slang phrase that talks about how IT experts present insights into technologies that could have a negative impact on something.\nThe term arose originally from a statement in the 1960s published by renowned Dutch programmer Edsger Wybe Dijkstra that criticized the prolific use of go-to statements in programming languages of the era.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Considered Harmful mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The \u201cELIZA effect\u201d is a term used to discuss progressive artificial intelligence.\nIt is the idea that people may falsely attach meanings of symbols or words that they ascribe to artificial intelligence in technologies.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does ELIZA Effect mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer programming, baz is one of several common placeholder names for variables.\nBaz comes to the IT world along with the more common placeholders foo and bar.\nThese names are simple ways to refer to universal ideas about the use of variables in programming.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Baz mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A carry flag in computer science works with the arithmetic\nlogic unit (ALU) of a computer's central processing unit to handle arithmetic and\nbitwise logical operations on binary numbers.\nThe carry flag is used when an\noperation changes the left-hand bit of the binary system.\nSome call this the\nmost significant or \u201cleftmost\u201d bit.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Carry Flag (C Flag) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The bucky bit in IT is an extension of binary code representing\na character or function that adds an eighth bit to the code through the pressing\nof a keyboard modifier key.\nThis can be done with keys like the Alt key, Control key, the Command key, the Meta key or the Option key.\nThe bucky bit is\nnamed after Niklaus \u201cBucky\u201d Wirth, who pioneered the use of\nthese modifying eighth bits at Stanford\nUniversity in the 1960s.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Bucky Bit mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A desk check is an informal non-computerized or manual\nprocess for verifying the programming and logic of an algorithm before the\nprogram is launched.\nA desk check helps programmers to find bugs and errors which\nwould prevent the application from functioning properly.\nAlthough a useful\ntechnique for spotting errors, modern debugging applications and tools have\nmade desk checks less relevant and not as essential as they previously were.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Desk Check mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Lexical analysis is a concept that is applied to computer\nscience in a very similar way that it is applied to linguistics.\nEssentially,\nlexical analysis means grouping a stream of letters or sounds into sets of\nunits that represent meaningful syntax.\nIn linguistics, it is called parsing,\nand in computer science, it can be called parsing or tokenizing.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Lexical Analysis mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The term \u201cmiddle-endian\u201d in IT describes a rather uncommon setup in computing hardware, where some minicomputers or other devices might store bytes of information in a less organized and consistent way than what is considered the industry standard.\nBy contrast, in little-endian design, the computing architecture stores the most significant bytes at lower addresses.\nIn a big-endian approach, the architecture stores the most significant bytes at higher addresses.\nA middle-endian approach happens when manufacturers use \u201cperverse byte orders\u201d (in the words of writers at the Jargon File) to encode the most significant bytes in the middle.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Middle-Endian mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A no operation or \u201cno-op\u201d instruction in an assembly language\nis an instruction that does not implement any operation.\nIT pros or others\nmight refer to this as a blank instruction or placeholder.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does No Operation (NOP) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The International Obfuscated C Code Contest (IOCCC), which has been held nearly annually since 1984, is a contest in which programmers compete to design intentionally cryptic, inefficient, unwieldy pieces of C code.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does International Obfuscated C Code Contest (IOCCC) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A non-maskable interrupt (NMI) is a type of hardware\ninterrupt (or signal to the processor) that prioritizes a certain thread\nor process.\nUnlike other types of interrupts, the non-maskable interrupt cannot\nbe ignored through the use of interrupt masking techniques.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Non-Maskable Interrupt (NMI) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An analog computer is a computer which is used to process\nanalog data.\nAnalog computers store\ndata in a continuous form of physical quantities and perform calculations with\nthe help of measures.\nIt is quite different from the digital computer, which\nmakes use of symbolic numbers to represent results.\nAnalog computers are excellent for situations which require\ndata to be measured directly without converting into numerals or codes.\nAnalog\ncomputers, although available and used in industrial and scientific applications\nlike control systems and aircraft, have been largely replaced by digital computers\ndue to the wide range of complexities involved.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Analog Computer mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Pattern matching in computer science is the checking and locating of specific sequences of data of some pattern among raw data or a sequence of tokens.\nUnlike pattern recognition, the match has to be exact in the case of pattern matching.\nPattern matching is one of the most fundamental and important paradigms in several programming languages.\nMany applications make use of pattern matching as a major part of their tasks.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Pattern Matching mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A storage snapshot can be defined as a set of\npointers to denote the data stored on a storage device.\nThis storage device\ncould be a disk drive, a tape or storage area network (SAN).\nIt can be thought\nof as a table of contents with each pointer describing the information or\ndata stored on the disk.\nThis snapshot is\ntreated by the computer as a complete backup of data.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Storage Snapshot mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computing systems, an overrun happens when there is too much demand placed on a system, where it is not able to handle all of the processes and threads that are happening.\nIT pros might talk about a \u201cCPU overrun\u201d when the CPU is not able to handle demand, or an \u201cinterface overrun\u201d when the OP crashes because of insufficient process handling capability.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Overrun mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An analog computer is a computer or device that uses\nphysical means, such as mechanical or hydraulic components to do computing\ntasks, rather than using electronic circuits to manipulate the results of\ndigital technologies.\nAnalog computers represented the earliest efforts of\nengineers to create powerful computing devices, where digital computers quickly\ntook over as technologies such as logic gates and circuit boards were\npioneered.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Analog Computing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Configuration is the manner in which components are arranged to make up the computer system.\nConfiguration consists of both hardware and software components.\nSometimes, people specifically point to hardware arrangement as hardware configuration and to software components as software configuration.\nUnderstanding of computer configuration is important as for certain hardware or software applications, a minimum configuration are required.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Configuration mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Extended binary coded decimal interchange code (EBCDIC) is an 8-bit binary code for numeric and alphanumeric characters.\nIt was developed and\nused by IBM.\nIt is a coding representation in which symbols, letters and numbers\nare presented in binary language.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Extended Binary Coded Decimal Interchange Code (EBCDIC) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "John McCarthy was a computer and cognitive scientist most notable for his great contributions in the field of artificial intelligence, where he is considered as one of the founders.\nHe also coined the term \"artificial intelligence\" and developed Lisp, one of the earliest programming languages, which is favored for use in AI research.\nHe received the Turing Award for his contributions in AI, the Kyoto Prize and the United States National Medal of Science, among many other honors and accolades.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does John McCarthy mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Reinforcement learning, in the context of artificial intelligence, is a type of dynamic programming that trains algorithms using a system of reward and punishment.\nA reinforcement learning algorithm, or agent, learns by interacting with its environment.\nThe agent receives rewards by performing correctly and penalties for performing incorrectly.\nThe agent learns without intervention from a human by maximizing its reward and minimizing its penalty.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Reinforcement Learning (RL) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "\"Offline\" refers to a device not connected to a network.\nIt may also be used for a device that is not working properly, such as an \"offline printer.\n\" Offline can additionally refer to the \"real world\" outside of the internet.\nThis is normally used to distinguish between online and offline communications, such as email vs.\n\"snail mail.\n\"\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Offline mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Isaac Asimov's Three Laws of Robotics are an invention of this author first pioneered in his 1942 story \u201cRunaround\u201d and then incorporated into the \u201cRobot\u201d series and \u201cFoundation\u201d series of books that Asimov generated over a period of time from the 1950s to the 1980s.\nAsimov's Three Laws of Robotics are proscriptive rules governing what robots can and cannot do, according to a fairly complex logical moral code.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Asimov's Three Laws Of Robotics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Analytic geometry is a kind of geometry using a coordinate system.\nThe kind familiar to most people is the two-dimensional plane using the x and y-axes.\nThree-dimensional analytic geometry adds a z-axis.\nBoth the 2-D and 3-D versions of analytic geometry are widely used in computer graphics to place objects on the screen.\nAnalytic geometry is also known as Cartesian geometry or Coordinate geometry.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Analytic Geometry mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Supervised learning is a method used to enable machines to classify objects, problems or situations based on related data fed into the machines.\nMachines are fed with data such as characteristics, patterns, dimensions, color and height of objects, people or situations repetitively until the machines are able to perform accurate classifications.\nSupervised learning is a popular technology or concept that is applied to real-life scenarios.\nSupervised learning is used to provide product recommendations, segment customers based on customer data, diagnose disease based on previous symptoms and perform many other tasks.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Supervised Learning mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Unsupervised learning is a method used to enable machines to classify both tangible and intangible objects without providing the machines any prior information about the objects.\nThe things machines need to classify are varied, such as customer purchasing habits, behavioral patterns of bacteria and hacker attacks.\nThe main idea behind unsupervised learning is to expose the machines to large volumes of varied data and allow it to learn and infer from the data.\nHowever, the machines must first be programmed to learn from data.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Unsupervised Learning mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Semi-supervised learning is a method used to enable machines to classify both tangible and intangible objects.\nThe objects the machines need to classify or identify could be as varied as inferring the learning patterns of students from classroom videos to drawing inferences from data theft attempts on servers.\nTo\nlearn and infer about objects, machines are provided labeled, shallow information about various types of data based on which the machines need to learn from large, structured and unstructured data they receive regularly.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Semi-Supervised Learning mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Automation is the creation of technology and its application in order to control and monitor the production and delivery of various goods and services.\nIt performs tasks that were previously performed by humans.\nAutomation is being used in a number of areas such as manufacturing, transport, utilities, defense, facilities, operations and lately, information technology.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Automation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A branch in a computer program is an instruction that tells a computer to begin executing different instructions rather than simply executing the instructions in order.\nIn high-level languages, these are typically referred to as flow control procedures and are built into the language.\nIn assembly programming, branch instructions are built into a CPU.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Branch mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Compute, in modern computing, refers to activities, applications or workloads that require more processing resources than its memory or I/O resource requirements.\nGenerally speaking, compute is used to describe concepts and objects geared towards computation and processing.\nFor example, CPUs, APUs and GPUs are considered compute resources while graphics processing applications like 3-D rendering and video games are described as compute-intensive applications.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Compute mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A hybrid Active Directory tool\nuses multiple methods or components to deal with identity access and other\nnetwork considerations.\nThe original MS Active Directory was designed to help\nadministrate a Windows domain.\nToday\u2019s access control and management paradigms\nmay be more sophisticated.\nA hybrid Active Directory tool is also known as a hybrid identity tool.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hybrid Active Directory mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A cloud archive is a service involving vendor storage of client data sets in the vendor\u2019s own infrastructure.\nLike other cloud services, the cloud archive happens through the web \u2013 data gets moved from on-premise, in-house systems to a cloud destination somewhere in the vendor\u2019s network.\nA cloud archive with data retrieval capability is one of the most basic and fundamental cloud services that vendors provide in today's technology.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cloud Archive mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "\u201cTarget platform\u201d is a generally used term in IT to discuss a platform of focus.\nA target platform can refer to the platform that\nsomething is being built for, a platform that is desirable for use, or simply a\nplatform that a particular technology is focusing on.\nThe use of these types of\nterms has become more common with multiplatform software and services that\nintegrate operations across a larger number of platforms.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Target Platform mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An identity life cycle is a term for the full life cycle\nof identity and access for a user on a given system.\nThis is often used in a\nbusiness context, when someone is talking about identity life cycle management,\nsystems that handle the entire context of someone accessing data on a company's\nnetwork.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Identity Life Cycle mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A fast Fourier transform (FFT) is an algorithm that calculates the\ndiscrete Fourier transform (DFT) of some sequence \u2013 the discrete Fourier transform\nis a tool to convert specific types of sequences of functions into other types\nof representations.\nAnother way to explain discrete Fourier transform is that it\ntransforms the structure of the cycle of a waveform into sine components.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fast Fourier Transform (FFT) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Edge scoring refers to a type of processing that internet of things (IoT) devices can do.\nWith edge processing, devices can actually perform the\nanalytics right there, where the data is collected, instead of sending the data back to a central\nmachine handling all the processing.\nThis saves a lot of bandwidth and\nprocessing power by distributing computation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Edge Scoring mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Wait-time analysis is a form of database performance tuning that focuses on reducing wait times for operations as much as possible.\nWait-time analysis looks at the time it takes for a database to complete operations.\nWith wait-time analysis, database administrators can see which operations are taking the most time and make appropriate adjustments.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Wait-Time Analysis mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computational geometry is a branch of computer science that studies algorithms which can be expressed in other forms of geometry.\nHistorically, it is considered one of the oldest fields in computing, although modern computational geometry is a recent development.\nThe primary reason for the development of computational geometry has been due to progress made in computer graphics, as well as computer-aided design and manufacturing.\nHowever, several problems tend to be classical in nature and come from mathematical visualization.\nApplications of computational geometry can be found in robotics, integrated circuit design, computer vision (3-D reconstruction), computer-aided engineering and geographic information systems (GIS)\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computational Geometry mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A computer simulation is the usage of a computer for the imitation of a real-world process or system.\nThe dynamic responses of one system are represented by the behavior of another system, which is largely modeled on the former.\nA simulation requires a model, or a mathematical description of the real system.\nThis is in the form of computer programs, which encompass the key characteristics or behaviors of the selected system.\nHere, the model is basically a representation of the system and the simulation process is known to depict the operation of the system in time.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer Simulation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Commodore SX-64 was a portable personal computer, the\nfirst of its kind to feature a full color display in 1983 when it was released.\nThe Commodore SX-64 had a 170k floppy disk drive, 64k of RAM, and a 5\u201d screen.\nIt ran on a Commodore BASIC operating system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Commodore SX-64 (SX-64) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Chaos theory is a particular mathematical field that studies\nthe properties of, and predictability of, deterministic systems, or systems\nthat are dependent on a base set of initial conditions.\nChaos theory may model\nthese systems in various ways, or try to make mathematical determinations about\nthese systems.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Chaos Theory mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Heterogeneous support is the support of heterogeneous service\narchitectures (HSAs) or computing systems.\nHeterogeneous support has to\ncontemplate the burden of support for various types of operations in the same\nuniversal system environment.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Heterogeneous Support mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Digital control is a branch of control\ntheory that makes use of digital computers for acting as controllers for a system.\nHere, a computer is responsible for the implementation of the control\nalgorithm.\nA digital control system is also capable of taking the form of a\nmicrocontroller to an application-specific integrated circuit and even to a\ndesktop computer, largely depending on the need.\nUsually, a digital control\nsystem consists of an A/D conversion for converting analog input to digital\nformat for the machine, D/A conversion for converting digital output to a form\nthat can be the input for a plant, and a digital controller in the form of a\ncomputer, microcontroller or a programmable logic controller.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Digital Control mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A digital filter is a system that performs mathematical operations on a discrete and sampled time signal,\nso as to enhance or reduce certain aspects of that particular signal as may be\nnecessary.\nIt is largely used in signal processing and differs from an analog\nfilter, which is an electronic circuit working with continuous signals.\nDigital\nfilters are expensive compared to analog ones, but they can turn many impractical or impossible designs into possibilities.\nIn everyday life, they can\nbe found in devices like cell phones, radios and audio/video receivers.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Digital Filter mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Universal mapping is an aspect of category theory that applies mathematical functions to various sciences and disciplines, such as algebra and computer science.\nIt includes identifying systems that can be universally applied over separate disciplines.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Universal Mapping mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computational fluid dynamics (CFD) is a\nbranch of physics that deals with the study of the mechanics of fluid:\nliquid, plasmas and gasses and forces acting on them.\nCFG is based on\nNavier-Stroke equations that describe how pressure, velocity, density and\ntemperature of a moving fluid are related.\nIt makes use of numerical methods, mathematical modeling and software\ntools to solve and analyze problems that involve fluid flows and uses the\nlatest in computer hardware and elegant programming techniques to model and\nsimulate liquid and gas interactions with surfaces, as defined by boundary\nconditions.\nThis gives insight into flow patterns that would be difficult,\nexpensive or impossible to study using traditional techniques.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computational Fluid Dynamics (CFD) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "VLAN tagging is a method through which more than one VLAN is handled on a port.\nVLAN tagging is used to tell which packet belongs to which VLAN on the other\nside.\nTo make recognition easier, a packet is tagged with a VLAN tag in the Ethernet\nframe.\nIndependent logical systems can be formed accurately with the help of\nthe VLAN tagging inside a physical network itself.\nIndividual domains can be\ncreated with the help of this VLAN tagging system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does VLAN Tagging mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A code generator is a tool or resource that generates a particular sort of code or computer programming language.\nThis has many specific meanings in the world of IT, many of them related to the sometimes complex processes of converting human programming syntax to the machine language that can be read by a computing system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Code Generator mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In frame relay networks, the committed information rate\n(CIR) is the bandwidth that is allocated to a logical connection in a permanent\nvirtual circuit (PVC).\nThe bandwidth is guaranteed by the provider even if\nother customers are sharing the same physical connection over frame relay.\nThe\nbandwidth is expressed in kilobits per second.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Committed Information Rate (CIR) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Exclusive or (XOR, EOR or EXOR) is a logical operator which results true when either of the operands are true (one is true and the other one is false) but both are not true and both are not false.\nIn logical condition making, the simple \"or\" is a bit ambiguous when both operands are true.\nBecause in that case it is very difficult to understand what exactly satisfies the condition.\nTo remove this ambiguity, the \"exclusive\" term has been added to \"or\" to make it more clear in meaning.\nExclusive or is also known as exclusive disjunction.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Exclusive Or (XOR) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In a network, a cluster controller is a machine that is used to manage other machines in a cluster.\nA cluster controller distributes jobs to the other machines for processing and receiving output from the other machines.\nThese cluster controllers have different names in different networks.\nIn Hadoop, for example, this cluster controller is called a NameNode.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cluster Controller mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A double-ended queue is a\nspecial type of data in the field of computer programming.\nIn this abstract data type,\nelements can be added from both the front and the back of the queue.\nDue to\nthis property, it is also known as a head-tail linked list.\nIn this, the queue\nactually symbolizes a collection of items arranged similarly to a line with two\nends.\nItems can be added or removed from either end without any type of\nrestrictions.\nMany programming languages use this technique due to its many\napplications.\nA double-ended queue is also known as a deque or a dequeue (pronounced \u201cdeck\u201d).\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Double-Ended Queue (Deque) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A direct connection is a situation in which one computer is directly linked\nto another computer by a cable instead of a network.\nThis might be using a\ncrossover cable instead of going through an Ethernet switch.\nThis kind of\nconnection is typically faster than using a network.\nThe two computers can transfer\ndata through this method.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Direct Connection mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Electromagnetism is a branch of physics which deals with\nstudy of electromagnetic force.\nBeing one of four fundamental interactions \u2013 along with gravitation, weak interaction and strong interaction \u2013 electromagnetic\nforce happens between electrically charged particles.\nDiscovered in the 19th century, electromagnetism has extensive usage in todays\u2019 physics.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Electromagnetism mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Response time, in the\ncontext of computer technology, is the elapsed time between an inquiry on a\nsystem and the response to that inquiry.\nUsed as a measurement of system performance, response time may refer to service requests in a variety of technologies.\nLow response times may be critical to successful computing.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Response Time mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An eye diagram is an indicator of quality in a serial bit stream.\nThe display (which has symmetrical patterns shaped similarly to eyes, hence the name) represents the integrity and consistency of data streams by visualizing the transitions between 0 and 1 values and comparing those transitions among the others in their stream.\nAn eye diagram is also known as an eye pattern.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Eye Diagram mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Disambiguation is the conceptual separation of two ideas represented by the same word, a word that has the same spelling, where it is difficult to tell which meaning is being referenced.\nHumans and technology systems both have their own means for disambiguation and methods for interpreting and parsing inputs.\nDisambiguation is also known as word sense disambiguation and text disambiguation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Disambiguation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Halt and Catch Fire (HCF) is a type of machine language\ninstruction that would cause the computer to cease operations.\nIt began as a\npurely theoretical instruction, but some firms have used actual HCF\ninstructions to diagnose computers or simulate certain events in a computer system.\nThe common definition of Halt and Catch Fire is that the instruction would\ncause the computer to lock up, and the user would need to restart it to be able\nto use it effectively.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Halt And Catch Fire (HCF) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "I/O controllers are a series of microchips which help in the communication of data between the central processing unit and the motherboard.\nThe main purpose of this system is to help in the interaction of peripheral devices with the control units (CUs).\nPut simply, the I/O controller helps in the connection and control of various peripheral devices, which are input and output devices.\nIt is usually installed on the motherboard of a computer.\nHowever, it can also be used as an accessory in the case of replacements or in order to add more peripheral devices to the computer.\nI/O controllers are also known as channel I/O, DMA controllers, peripheral processors or I/O processors.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does I/O Controller (IOC) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A logic error is an error in a program\u2019s source code that\ngives way to unanticipated and erroneous behavior.\nA logic error is classified as a type of runtime\nerror that can result in a program producing an incorrect output.\nIt can also cause\nthe program to crash when running.\nLogic errors are\nnot always easy to recognize immediately.\nThis is due to the fact that such\nerrors, unlike that of syntax errors, are valid when considered in the language,\nbut do not produce the intended behavior.\nThese can occur in both interpreted\nand compiled languages.\nA logic error is also known as a logical error.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Logic Error mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "K-means clustering is a simple unsupervised learning\nalgorithm that is used to solve clustering problems.\nIt follows a simple\nprocedure of classifying a given data set into a number of clusters, defined by\nthe letter \"k,\" which is fixed beforehand.\nThe clusters are then positioned as\npoints and all observations or data points are associated with the nearest\ncluster, computed, adjusted and then the process starts over using the new\nadjustments until a desired result is reached.\nK-means clustering has uses in search engines, market segmentation, statistics and even astronomy.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does K-Means Clustering mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Boolean algebra is a type of mathematical operation that, unlike regular algebra, works with binary digits (bits): 0 and 1.\nWhile 1 represents true, 0 represents false.\nComputers can perform simple to extremely complex operations with the use of Boolean algebra.\nBoolean algebra and Boolean operations are the basis for computer logic.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Boolean Algebra mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computer vision is a field of computer science that works on enabling computers to see, identify and process images in the same way that human vision does, and then provide appropriate output.\nIt is like imparting human intelligence and instincts to a computer.\nIn reality though, it is a difficult task to enable computers to recognize images of different objects.\nComputer vision is closely linked with artificial intelligence, as the computer must interpret what it sees, and then perform appropriate analysis or act accordingly.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computer Vision mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The European Research Consortium for Informatics and Mathematics (ERCIM) is a research consortium focused on research projects in computer science and mathematics.\nFounded in 1988, ERCIM has members from leading European information technology and mathematics research establishments from 18 countries.\nThe nonprofit organization's aim is to foster collaborative work and improve cooperation within European industry and the European research community.\nApart from hosting the European branch of the World Wide Web Consortium (W3C), the European Research Consortium for Informatics and Mathematics is a major representative organization in its area.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does European Research Consortium for Informatics and Mathematics (ERCIM) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In software programming, a block code is used to convert software code or an algorithm into any particular form so that errors, if any, in the code can be minimized.\nBlock code can also be applied in the domains of telecommunications, information theory and coding theory.\nThe main idea is to encode a message for a recipient in such a way that the recipient is able to address errors, if any, in the message with the help of the encoding.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Block Code mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Core Operating System (Core OS) is a system for container-based virtualization.\nCore OS deploys applications in virtual containers as a way to provide effective hardware virtualization for businesses.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Core Operating System (Core OS) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The halting problem, commonly applied to Turing-complete programs and models, is the problem of finding out whether, with the given input, a program will halt at some time or continue to run indefinitely.\nThe halting problem is an early example of a decision problem, and also a good example of the limits of determinism in computer science.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Halting Problem mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A fuzzy search process is one that applies search algorithms in a more lenient way than hard search algorithms that only match specific and rigid results.\nFuzzy search can be much more effective for some kinds of searches, because although it may turn out less relevant search results, it may also turn out highly relevant search results that would have been screened out by an excessively rigid search algorithm.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fuzzy Search mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Concurrency \u2014 in the context of programming \u2014 is the ability for a program to be decomposed into parts that can run independently of each other.\nThis means that tasks can be executed out of order and the result would still be the same as if they are executed in order.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Programming Concurrency mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In Unix-like operating systems, a sticky bit is a permission bit which is set on a file or folder, thereby permitting only the owner or root user of the file or\nfolder to modify, rename or delete the concerned directory or file.\nNo other user would be permitted to have these privileges on a file which has a sticky bit.\nIn Unix-like systems, without the sticky bit on, any user can modify, rename or delete the directory or file regardless of the owner of the file or folder.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Sticky Bit mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Gaussian mixture model (GMM) is a category of probabilistic model which states that all generated data points are derived from a mixture of a finite Gaussian distributions that has no known parameters.\nThe parameters for Gaussian mixture models are derived either from maximum a posteriori estimation or an iterative expectation-maximization algorithm from a prior model which is well trained.\nGaussian mixture models are very useful when it comes to modeling data, especially data which comes from several groups.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Gaussian Mixture Model (GMM) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A binary search algorithm is used to find the position of a specific value contained in a sorted array.\nWorking with the principle of divide and conquer, this search algorithm can be quite fast, but the caveat is that the data has to be in a sorted form.\nIt works by starting the search in the middle of the array and working going down the first lower or upper half of the sequence.\nIf the median value is lower than the target value, that means that the search needs to go higher, if not, then it needs to look on the descending portion of the array.\nA binary search is also known as a half-interval search or logarithmic search.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Binary Search mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computing, the most significant bit (MSB) is the bit which has the largest value in a multi-bit binary number.\nThe most significant bit is the one which is farthest to the left.\nAs binary numbers are largely used in computing and other related areas, the most significant bit holds importance, especially when it comes to transmission of a binary number.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Most Significant Bit (MSB) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Huffman coding is a lossless data encoding algorithm.\nThe process behind its scheme includes sorting numerical values from a set in order of their frequency.\nThe least frequent numbers are gradually eliminated via the Huffman tree, which adds the two lowest frequencies from the sorted list in every new \u201cbranch.\n\u201d The sum is then positioned above the two eliminated lower frequency values, and replaces them in the new sorted list.\nEach time a new branch is created, it moves the general direction of the tree either to the right (for higher values) or the left (for lower values).\nWhen the sorted list is exhausted and the tree is complete, the final value is zero if the tree ended on a left number, or it is one if it ended on the right.\nThis is a method of reducing complex code into simpler sequences and is common in video encoding.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Huffman Coding mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A half adder is a type of adder, an electronic circuit that performs the addition of numbers.\nThe half adder is able to add two single binary digits and provide the output plus a carry value.\nIt has two inputs, called A and B, and two outputs S (sum) and C (carry).\nThe common representation uses a XOR logic gate and an AND logic gate.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Half Adder mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computing, the least significant bit is the bit which is farthest to the right and holds the least value in a multi-bit binary number.\nAs binary numbers are largely used in computing and other related areas, the least significant bit holds importance, especially when it comes to transmission of binary numbers.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Least Significant Bit (LSB) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In mathematics, modular arithmetic is special category of arithmetic that makes use of only integers.\nIn other words, modular arithmetic is the arithmetic of congruence.\nModular arithmetic is sometimes known as clock arithmetic, as one of the most familiar uses of modular arithmetic is in the 12-hour clock, which has the time period divided into two equal halves.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Modular Arithmetic mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "With a decimal number system, a decimal point is used to denote the decimal part of the number.\nUnlike the separators used for digit grouping such as the thousands separator, no separators are used to the right of the decimal point.\nDifferent countries officially designate different symbols for the decimal point.\nIn most English-speaking countries, the decimal point is usually denoted by a period/dot to separate the whole number from its fractional parts.\nHowever, in continental Europe, the decimal point is usually denoted with the comma.\nThe decimal point is also known as a decimal mark.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Decimal Point mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A greedy algorithm is an algorithmic strategy that makes the best optimal choice at each small stage with the goal of this eventually leading to a globally optimum solution.\nThis means that the algorithm picks the best solution at the moment without regard for consequences.\nIt picks the best immediate output, but does not consider the big picture, hence it is considered greedy.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Greedy Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In logic, a quantifier is a language element that helps in generation of a quantification, which is a construct that mentions the number of specimens in the given domain of discourse satisfying a given open formula.\nQuantifiers are largely used in logic, natural languages and discrete mathematics.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Quantifier mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Digital logic is the underlying logic system that drives electronic circuit board design.\nDigital logic is the manipulation of binary values through printed circuit board technology that uses circuits and logic gates to construct the implementation of computer operations.\nDigital logic is a common part of electrical engineering and design courses.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Digital Logic mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A bipartite graph is a graph in which a set of graph vertices can be divided into two independent sets, and no two graph vertices within the same set are adjacent.\nIn other words, bipartite graphs can be considered as equal to two colorable graphs.\nBipartite graphs are mostly used in modeling relationships, especially between two entire separate classes of object.\nA bipartite graph is also known as a bigraph.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Bipartite Graph mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "For most operating systems, a file descriptor (FD) is a small non-negative integer that helps in identifying an open file within a process while using input/output resources like network sockets or pipes.\nIn a way, it can be considered as an index table of open files.\nWhen there are read, write or closing file operations, one of the input parameters considered is the file descriptor.\nFile descriptors form an important component of POSIX application programming interface and provide a primitive, low-level interface to input or output operations.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does File Descriptor (FD) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An absolute path refers to the complete details needed to locate a file or folder, starting from the root element and ending with the other subdirectories.\nAbsolute paths are used in websites and operating systems for locating files and folders.\nAn absolute path is also known as an absolute pathname or full path.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Absolute Path mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A truth table is a tabular representation of all the combinations of values for inputs and their corresponding outputs.\nIt is a mathematical table that shows all possible outcomes that would occur from all possible scenarios that are considered factual, hence the name.\nTruth tables are usually used for logic problems as in Boolean algebra and electronic circuits.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Truth Table mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Reverse Polish notation (RPN) is a method for conveying mathematical expressions without the use of separators such as brackets and parentheses.\nIn this notation, the operators follow their operands, hence removing the need for brackets to define evaluation priority.\nThe operation is read from left to right but execution is done every time an operator is reached, and always using the last two numbers as the operands.\nThis notation is suited for computers and calculators since there are fewer characters to track and fewer operations to execute.\nReverse Polish notation is also known as postfix notation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Reverse Polish Notation (RPN) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science and logic, unification is the algorithmic procedure used in solving equations involving symbolic expressions.\nIn other words, by replacing certain sub-expression variables with other expressions, unification tries to identify two symbolic expressions.\nUnification is used in automated reasoning technology, which remains one of the major application areas of unification.\nUnification is used in implementations such as:Programming language-type system implementationLogic programmingSMT solversCryptographic protocol analysisTerm-rewriting algorithmsUnification is one of the fundamental techniques upon which methods for automated deduction are based.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Unification mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An abstract syntax tree (AST) is a way of representing the syntax of a programming language as a hierarchical tree-like structure.\nThis structure is used for generating symbol tables for compilers and later code generation.\nThe tree represents all of the constructs in the language and their subsequent rules.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Abstract Syntax Tree (AST) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science, an abstract data type is a theoretical data type that is largely defined by the operations and work on it and the limitations that apply.\nProfessionals describe an abstract data type as a \u201cmathematical model\u201d for groups of data types, or as a \u201cvalue with associated operations\u201d that is independent of a particular implementation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Abstract Data Type mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Branch prediction is an approach to computer architecture that attempts to mitigate the costs of branching.\nBranch predication speeds up the processing of branch instructions with CPUs using pipelining.\nThe technique involves only executing certain instructions if certain predicates are true.\nBranch prediction is typically implemented in hardware using a branch predictor.\nBranch prediction is also known as branch predication or simply as predication.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Branch Prediction mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Information theory is a branch of mathematics that defines efficient and practical methods by which data can be exchanged and interpreted.\nThe concept originated in a mid-twentieth century essay by a mathematician by the name of Claude Shannon, which set many important precedents for digital technology, including the usage of bits as units of measurement.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Information Theory mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Interpolation is the estimation of a value or set of values based on their context.\nLinear interpolation, a very simple form of interpolation, is basically the rendering of a straight line between two or more points.\nInterpolation is useful for filling in missing data, such as in upscaling images or creating statistical models.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Interpolation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A binary counter is a hardware circuit that is made out of a series of flip-flops.\nThe output of one flip-flop is sent to the input of the next flip-flop in the series.\nA binary counter can be either asynchronous or synchronous, depending on how the flip-flops are connected together.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Binary Counter mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Cartesian coordinates specify the position of points on a two-dimensional or three-dimensional plane.\nThey are based on the coordinate system developed by mathematician and philosopher Rene Descartes.\nCartesian coordinates consist of numbered lines on two or three axes, dubbed the x, y and z axes.\nIn computing, these coordinates are widely used for graphics programming.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cartesian Coordinates mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computational science is the application of computer science and software engineering principles to solving scientific problems.\nIt involves the use of computing hardware, networking, algorithms, programming, databases and other domain-specific knowledge to design simulations of physical phenomena to run on computers.\nComputational science crosses disciplines and can even involve the humanities.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computational Science mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Insertion sort is a sorting algorithm in which the elements are transferred one at a time to the right position.\nIn other words, an insertion sort helps in building the final sorted list, one item at a time, with the movement of higher-ranked elements.\nAn insertion sort has the benefits of simplicity and low overhead.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Insertion Sort mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science, a monoid is a specific data set defined, as by the etymology of the word, as a single unit.\nThe monoid is a unit within the greater structure of a \u201csemi-group\u201d \u2013 in mathematics, it is an algebraic entity broken down into an individual category from the semi-group, which is defined as a set with an associative binary operation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Monoid mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A syntax error in computer science is an error in the syntax of a coding or programming language, entered by a programmer.\nSyntax errors are caught by a software program called a compiler, and the programmer must fix them before the program is compiled and then run.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Syntax Error mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Viterbi algorithm is an algorithm for analyzing a series of hidden states called the Viterbi path.\nThis model is often used in the context of a Markov source, or a source where random variables present significant unknowns.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Viterbi Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Memory capacity is the amount of memory that can be used for an electronic device such as a computer, laptop, smartphone or other smart device.\nEvery hardware device or computer has a minimum and maximum amount of memory.\nThe performance of a device and the efficiency of its input/output operations is dependent on memory capacity.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Memory Capacity mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Conjunctive normal form (CNF) is an approach to Boolean logic that expresses formulas as conjunctions of clauses with an AND or OR.\nEach clause connected by a conjunction, or AND, must be either a literal or contain a disjunction, or OR operator.\nCNF is useful for automated theorem proving.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Conjunctive Normal Form (CNF) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Magnetic permeability (\u03bc) is the ability of a magnetic material to support magnetic field development.\nIn other words, magnetic permeability is the constant in the proportionality between magnetic induction and magnetic field intensity.\nThe greater the magnetic permeability of the material, the greater the conductivity for magnetic lines of force, and vice versa.\nThe magnetic permeability of a material indicates the ease with which an external magnetic field can create a higher magnetic force of attraction in the material.\nThe SI unit of magnetic permeability is Henry per meter.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Magnetic Permeability (\u00b5) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A full adder is a digital circuit that performs addition.\nFull adders are implemented with logic gates in hardware.\nA full adder adds three one-bit binary numbers, two operands and a carry bit.\nThe adder outputs two numbers, a sum and a carry bit.\nThe term is contrasted with a half adder, which adds two binary digits.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Full Adder mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A doubly linked list is a linked list data structure that includes a link back to the previous node in each node in the structure.\nThis is contrasted with a singly linked list where each node only has a link to the next node in the list.\nDoubly linked lists also include a field and a link to the next node in the list.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Doubly Linked List mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A program counter (PC) is a CPU register in the computer processor which has the address of the next instruction to be executed from memory.\nIt is a digital counter needed for faster execution of tasks as well as for tracking the current execution point.\nA program counter is also known as an instruction counter, instruction pointer, instruction address register or sequence control register.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Program Counter (PC) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science and mathematics, a directed acyclic graph (DAG) is a graph that is directed and without cycles connecting the other edges.\nThis means that it is impossible to traverse the entire graph starting at one edge.\nThe edges of the directed graph only go one way.\nThe graph is a topological sorting, where each node is in a certain order.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Directed Acyclic Graph (DAG) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Linear interpolation is a form of interpolation, which involves the generation of new values based on an existing set of values.\nLinear interpolation is achieved by geometrically rendering a straight line between two adjacent points on a graph or plane.\nAll points on the line other than the original two can be considered interpolated values.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Linear Interpolation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An invariant is a value or condition that is expected to be consistent during the execution of a process.\nInvariants are useful in testing the results of algorithms and the integrity of computer programs.\nTheir predictability can simplify the process of assessing the validity of logical assertions, and invariants can be seen as points of reference within surrounding context.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Invariant mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A power inverter is a piece of equipment that transforms direct current (DC) electricity to alternating current (AC) electricity.\nBatteries produce direct current electricity, and a common implementation of power inverters is car batteries as a source for indoor power during power outages (for common household appliances that are powered by alternating current).\nPower inverters are sold as consumer items and are typically simple to install.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Power Inverter mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Extensibility is a measurement of a piece of technology\u2019s capacity to append additional elements and features to its existing structure.\nA software program, for example, is considered extensible when its operations may be augmented with add-ons and plugins.\nExtensible programming languages have the ability to define new features and introduce new functionality within them.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Extensible mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A metafile is a file that contains specifications for another file.\nMetafiles are commonly associated with digital graphics, particularly vector images.\nHowever metafiles can contain other formats as well, such as bitmaps or other data.\nMetafiles that contain audio, video and (in some cases) text are often referred to as container files.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Metafile mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Graph coloring in computer science refers to coloring certain parts of a visual graph, often in digital form.\nHowever, IT professionals also use the term to talk about the particular constraint satisfaction problem or NP-complete problem of assigning specific colors to graph segments.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Graph Coloring mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Truncation in IT refers to \u201ccutting\u201d something, or removing parts of it to make it shorter.\nIn general, truncation takes a certain object such as a number or text string and reduces it in some way, which makes it less resources to store.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Truncate mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Microarchitecture, abbreviated as \u00b5arch or uarch, is the fundamental design of a microprocessor.\nIt includes the technologies used, resources and the methods by which the processor is physically designed in order to execute a specific instruction set (ISA or instruction set architecture).\nSimply put, it is the logical design of all electronic components and data paths present in the microprocessor, laid out in a specific way that it allows for optimal execution of instructions.\nIn academe this is called computer organization.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Microarchitecture (\u00b5arch) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Backtracking is an algorithm for capturing some or all solutions to given computational issues, especially for constraint satisfaction issues.\nThe algorithm can only be used for problems which can accept the concept of a \u201cpartial candidate solution\u201d and allows a quick test to see if the candidate solution can be a complete solution.\nBacktracking is considered an important technique to solve constraint satisfaction issues and puzzles.\nIt is also considered a great technique for parsing and also forms the basis of many logic programming languages.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Backtracking mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Polish notation is a notation form for expressing arithmetic, logic and algebraic equations.\nIts most basic distinguishing feature is that operators are placed on the left of their operands.\nIf the operator has a defined fixed number of operands, the syntax does not require brackets or parenthesis to lessen ambiguity.\nPolish notation is also known as prefix notation, prefix Polish notation, normal Polish notation, Warsaw notation and Lukasiewicz notation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Polish Notation (PN) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Gray code evaluates the nature of binary code or data that is composed of on and off indicators, commonly represented by ones and zeros.\nDeveloped by Bell Labs scientists, gray code has been used to look at clarity and error correction in binary communications.\nGray code is also known as reflected binary code.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Gray Code mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Hamming distance in information technology represents the number of points at which two corresponding pieces of data can be different.\nIt is often used in various kinds of error correction or evaluation of contrasting strings or pieces of data.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hamming Distance mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Harvard architecture is a term for a computer system that contains two separate areas for commands or instructions and data.\nIn the Harvard architecture, the media, format and nature of the two different parts of the system may be different, as the two systems are represented by two separate structures.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Harvard Architecture mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In mathematics, a finite field is a field that contains a finite number of elements.\nIn other words, a finite field is a finite set on which the four basic operations \u2013 addition, subtraction, multiplication and division (excluding division by zero) \u2013 are defined and satisfy the field axioms/rules of the arithmetic.\nFinite fields are an important area of mathematics and computer science and are widely used in geometry, finite geometry, algebraic geometry, number theory, coding theory and cryptography.\nA finite field is also known as Galois field.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Finite Field mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Decision automation is the use of software to automatically make choices in business.\nIt is distinct from a decision support system because the software can actually make decisions instead of just offering information to humans who then make decisions.\nDecision automation makes choices based on preprogrammed business rules.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Decision Automation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Prefetching is the loading of a resource before it is required to decrease the time waiting for that resource.\nExamples include instruction prefetching where a CPU caches data and instruction blocks before they are executed, or a web browser requesting copies of commonly accessed web pages.\nPrefetching functions often make use of a cache.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Prefetching mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Big O notation is a particular tool for assessing algorithm efficiency.\nBig O notation is often used to show how programs need resources relative to their input size.\nBig O notation is also known as Bachmann\u2013Landau notation after its discoverers, or asymptotic notation.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Big O Notation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Monte Carlo algorithm is a type of resource-restricted algorithm that returns answers based on probability.\nAs a result, the solutions produced by the Monte Carlo algorithm may or may not be correct within a certain margin of error.\nMathematicians, scientists and developers use Monte Carlo algorithms to make observations based on input.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Monte Carlo Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Kleene star, in the parlance of computer science, is a programming resource that offers outcomes related to the concatenation of a string set.\nUsing the Kleene star, developers and others assess how to filter given results based on input.\nA Kleene star is also known as a Kleene operator or Kleene closure.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Kleene Star mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Petri nets are specific types of modeling constructs useful in data analysis, simulations, business process modeling and other scenarios.\nThis type of mathematical construct can help to plan workflows or present data on complicated systems.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Petri Net mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A quadtree is a type of data structure where each original or parent node has four lower-level or subsequent child nodes, where each element is continually split into four pieces.\nExpressed in mathematical equations or in a visual way, a quadtree has many data analysis applications.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Quadtree mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In general, binary describes anything that is made up of two things or parts.\nIn the context of information technology, binary is a base-2 numbering system that uses the numerals 0 and 1 for counting.\nIt is used by digital computers to perform calculations from the simplest to the most complex.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Binary mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Banach space is a complete normed vector space in mathematical analysis.\nThat is, the distance between vectors converges closer to each other as the sequence goes on.\nThe term is named after the Polish mathematician Stefan Banach (1892\u20131945), who is credited as one of the founders of functional analysis.\nIn computer science, the mathematician Shahar Mendelson has used the Banach space in machine learning to bound the errors of machine learning algorithms.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Banach Space mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A race condition is a behavior which occurs in software applications or electronic systems, such as logic systems, where the output is dependent on the timing or sequence of other uncontrollable events.\nRace conditions also occur in software which supports multithreading, use a distributed environment or are interdependent on shared resources.\nRace conditions often lead to bugs, as these events happen in a manner that the system or programmer never intended for.\nIt can often result in a device crash, error notification or shutdown of the application.\nA race condition is also known as a race hazard.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Race Condition mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A hard link is a link that directly associates a name with a given file in an operating system.\nUnlike a soft link, which changes the pointer when the file is renamed, a hard link still points to the underlying file even if the file name changes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hard Link mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An outer join in SQL is a specific kind of query construction that deliberately allows for a wider array of results.\nThe process of building specific queries in SQL to get database results is a highly technical one, and an outer join is an example of a type of detail learned and utilized by database researchers.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Outer Join mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Queueing theory is the study of queueing systems in which individual objects are processed in a linear way.\nThis type of observational process is useful in IT system engineering and other fields.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Queueing Theory mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Rete algorithm is an example of an algorithm that matches production rules.\nThe Rete algorithm uses a knowledge base to check production rules and provide outcomes accordingly.\nIt uses a complex node system to return results.\nTools such as joins determine the algorithm\u2019s behavior in terms of analysis.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Rete Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The term \u201cidempotent\u201d in IT refers to an operation that does not affect the application that it is called in, if it is called more than once with the same input parameters.\nOther kinds of operations change the application's data structure with each iteration.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Idempotence mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science, a control flow graph (CFG) is the graphical representation of control flow or computation during the execution of programs or applications.\nControl flow graphs are mostly used in static analysis as well as compiler applications, as they can accurately represent the flow inside of a program unit.\nThe control flow graph owes much of its development to Frances E.\nAllen.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Control Flow Graph (CFG) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The OR operator is a Boolean operator which would return the value TRUE or Boolean value of 1 if either or both of the operands are TRUE or have Boolean value of 1.\nThe OR operator is considered one of the basic logical operators along with AND and NOT in Boolean algebra.\nIt is widely used in programming languages which support logical and comparison operators.\nThe OR operator can also be used in combination with other logical operators.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does OR Operator mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Underflow is a condition which occurs in a computer or similar device when a mathematical operation results in a number which is smaller than what the device is capable of storing.\nIt is the opposite of overflow, which relates to a mathematical operation resulting in a number which is bigger than what the machine can store.\nSimilar to overflow, underflow can cause significant errors.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Underflow mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Fourier series is a representation of a wave form or other periodic function as a sum of sines and cosines.\nIt is named after the French mathematician and physicist Jean-Baptiste Joseph Fourier (1768\u20131830).\nSince sound waves are made up of sine waves, Fourier transforms are widely used in signal processing.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fourier Series mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In the context of computing, decimal refers to the base-10 numbering system.\nIt is the way humans read numbers.\nIn general, decimal can be anything that is based on the number 10.\nUnderstanding how decimal relates to binary, octal and hexadecimal is essential for those working in the IT industry.\nOther terms for decimal are base-10 and denary.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Decimal mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A non-deterministic algorithm can provide different outputs for the same input on different executions.\nUnlike a deterministic algorithm which produces only a single output for the same input even on different runs, a non-deterministic algorithm travels in various routes to arrive at the different outcomes.\nNon-deterministic algorithms are useful for finding approximate solutions, when an exact solution is difficult or expensive to derive using a deterministic algorithm.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Non-Deterministic Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computers, the clock cycle is the amount of time between two pulses of an oscillator.\nIt is a single increment of the central processing unit (CPU) clock during which the smallest unit of processor activity is carried out.\nThe clock cycle helps in determining the speed of the CPU, as it is considered the basic unit of measuring how fast an instruction can be executed by the computer processor.\nA clock cycle is also known as a clock tick.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Clock Cycle mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A keepalive is a signal sent from one device to another to\nmaintain a connection between the two devices.\nThis may be between a client and\na server, but it could apply to any number of devices or technologies.\nKeepalives are used in network environments to maintain an open communication\npathway, or to regularly check the status of a connection to a remote device.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Keepalive mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Reification is the process during which an abstract idea regarding a computer application can be converted into an object or explicit data model.\nIn other words, reification helps in the conversion of an unexpressed, implicit idea into a conceptual or logical one.\nReification is one the most widely used processes in knowledge representation and conceptual analysis.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": " Definition - What does Reification mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A multilayer perceptron (MLP) is a feedforward artificial neural network that generates a set of outputs from a set of inputs.\nAn MLP is characterized by several layers of input nodes connected as a directed graph between the input and output layers.\nMLP uses backpropogation for training the network.\nMLP is a deep learning method.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Multilayer Perceptron (MLP) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A linear feedback shift register (LSFR) is a shift register that takes a linear function of a previous state as an input.\nMost commonly, this function is a Boolean exclusive OR (XOR).\nThe bits that affect the state in the other bits are known as taps.\nLSFRs are used for digital counters, cryptography and circuit testing.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Linear Feedback Shift Register (LFSR) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Octal refers to the base-8 numbering system.\nIt comes from the Latin word for eight.\nThe octal numbering system uses the numerals 0-1-2-3-4-5-6-7.\nIn computing environments, it is commonly used as a shorter representation of binary numbers by grouping binary digits into threes.\nThe chmod command in Linux or UNIX uses octal to assign file permissions.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Octal mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The dining philosophers problem is a classic example in computer science often used to illustrate synchronization issues and solutions in concurrent algorithm design.\nIt illustrates the challenges of avoiding a system state where progress is not possible, a deadlock.\nThe problem was created in 1965 by E.\nW.\nDijkstra.\nPresented as a student exam exercise, the problem illustrates a number of computers competing for access to tape drive peripherals.\nThe formulation known today was a later revision by Tony Hoare.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Dining Philosophers Problem mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A von Neumann architecture machine, designed by physicist and mathematician John von Neumann (1903\u20131957) is a theoretical design for a stored program computer that serves as the basis for almost all modern computers.\nA von Neumann machine consists of a central processor with an arithmetic/logic unit and a control unit, a memory, mass storage, and input and output.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Von Neumann Architecture mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In networking, a hop count is the total number of intermediate devices such as routers through which a given piece of data must pass between the source and destination, instead of flowing directly over a single wire.\nAlong the data path, each router forms a hop, with data moving from one source to another.\nThe hop count is considered a basic measurement of the distance in a given network.\nIn other words, it gives an approximate measure of the distance between two given hosts.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hop Count mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computing, text processing is the automated mechanization of the creation or modification of electronic text.\nComputer commands are usually involved in text processing, which help in creating new content or bringing changes to content, searching or replacing content, formatting the content or generating a refined report of the content.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Text Processing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Cognitive technology is a field of computer science that mimics functions of the human brain through various means, including natural language processing, data mining and pattern recognition.\nIt is expected to have a drastic effect on the way that humans interact with technology in coming years, particularly in the fields of automation, machine learning and information technology.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cognitive Technology mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "DNA computing is the use of biomolecular components rather than standard artificial hardware (such as silicon chips) in computer technology.\nIn place of traditional code (such as the common binary variety), DNA computing utilizes the four-character genetic alphabet, which consists of:A \u2013 AdenineG \u2013 GuanineC \u2013 CytosineT \u2013 Thymine","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does DNA Computing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Ternary is a term for base-three arithmetic.\nA ternary number system can contain a total of three digits, such as 0, 1 and 2 (as opposed to something like binary code, which is often expressed through ones and zeros).\nBase-three number systems have many different applications, particularly in computer science and programming.\nTernary is also known as trinary.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Ternary mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The knapsack problem is an optimization problem used to illustrate both problem and solution.\nIt derives its name from a scenario where one is constrained in the number of items that can be placed inside a fixed-size knapsack.\nGiven a set of items with specific weights and values, the aim is to get as much value into the knapsack as possible given the weight constraint of the knapsack.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Knapsack Problem mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "\u201cHot\u201d migration in IT is the process of migrating a system that is operational and active.\nThis is in contrast to the practice of cold migration, where the migration occurs in a system that has been turned off or rendered non-operational.\nHot migration is also known as live migration.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hot Migration mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Cold migration is the process of migrating a system that has been turned off or rendered non-operational for a time.\nThis is in contrast to the practice of live migration or hot migration, where the migration occurs during the system\u2019s normal operations.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cold Migration mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An arithmetic shift in computer science involves a bitwise operation shifting binary numbers to an adjacent position, or some other position, either right or left.\nArithmetic shifts can help perform multiplication or division on binary numbers.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Arithmetic Shift mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Dirty bit is a colloquial name for a specific bit in computer memory that traditional computing systems use to indicate a modification or write-to.\nAlthough there is not much information on the origin of this term, one could understand the concept of the dirty bit being a temporary place marker that will eventually be erased.\nA dirty bit is also known as a modified bit.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Dirty Bit mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A backtick in computer science represents a \u201cshell\u201d form of command structure that some call a \u201cdouble operator.\n\u201d Essentially, the use of backticks allows for evaluating a string as part of a general command.\nIt may be used in computing languages like Perl or other types of code.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Backtick mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An expression tree is a representation of expressions arranged in a tree-like data structure.\nIn other words, it is a tree with leaves as operands of the expression and nodes contain the operators.\nSimilar to other data structures, data interaction is also possible in an expression tree.\nExpression trees are mainly used for analyzing, evaluating and modifying expressions, especially complex expressions.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Expression Tree mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science, random access is the capability to have access to any item from a given population of elements at random.\nRandom access is the opposite of sequential access, as sequential access locates elements by beginning at a particular predefined location and then traversing through all of the information in order to find the given item.\nRandom access has gained interest due to the fact that one can retrieve a record irrespective of the position in which it is located.\nRandom access is also known as direct access.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Random Access mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Temporal logic is a branch of symbolic logic which is concerned with problems on propositions that have truth values dependent on time.\nTemporal logic is considered a variant of modal logic, which is a branch of logic dealing with propositions that can be expressed as a set of possible worlds.\nTemporal logic is used to touch all approaches to reasoning and representation based on time.\nApplications of temporal logic include use in reasoning in philosophical issues based on time, as a language in artificial language for encoding temporal knowledge, and as tool for formal analysis, specification and verification of hardware and software requirements of computer applications and systems.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Temporal Logic mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In Boolean algebra, the NOT operator is a Boolean operator that returns TRUE or 1 when the operand is FALSE or 0, and returns FALSE or 0 when the operand is TRUE or 1.\nEssentially, the operator reverses the logical value associated with the expression on which it operates.\nThe NOT operator is considered one of the basic operators along with AND and OR in Boolean algebra.\nThe NOT operator is also known as the logical NOT.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does NOT Operator mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science, denotational semantics is an approach for providing mathematical meaning to systems and programming languages.\nIn other words, denotational semantics is a formal technique for expressing the semantic definition of a programming language.\nDeveloped in 1960s at Oxford University by Christopher Strachey's Programming Research Group, the methodology comprises notational elegance and mathematical rigor.\nAlthough initially designed as an analysis tool, denotational semantics has been used as a tool for implementation and language design.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Denotational Semantics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An outlier, in mathematics, statistics and information technology, is a specific data point that falls outside the range of probability for a data set.\nIn other words, the outlier is distinct from other surrounding data points in a particular way.\nOutlier analysis is extremely useful in various kinds of analytics and research, some of it related to technologies and IT systems.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Outlier mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Principal component analysis (PCA) is a technique used for identification of a smaller number of uncorrelated variables known as principal components from a larger set of data.\nThe technique is widely used to emphasize variation and capture strong patterns in a data set.\nInvented by Karl Pearson in 1901, principal component analysis is a tool used in predictive models and exploratory data analysis.\nPrincipal component analysis is considered a useful statistical method and used in fields such as image compression, face recognition, neuroscience and computer graphics.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Principal Component Analysis (PCA) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Mining, in the context of blockchain technology, is the process of adding transactions to the large distributed public ledger of existing transactions, known as the blockchain.\nThe term is best known for its association with bitcoin, though other technologies using the blockcahin employ mining.\nBitcoin mining rewards people who run mining operations with more bitcoins.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Mining mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Independent component analysis (ICA) is a way to get certain hidden information out of a signal.\nExperts define it as a \u201cmultivariate data model\u201d that brings non-Gaussian and mutually independent elements out of a combined signal.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Independent Component Analysis (ICA) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Microservices is the idea of offering a broader platform, application or service as a collection of combined services.\nThese microservices provide specialized, fine-grained cooperation that makes up the more comprehensive architecture model.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Microservices mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Ground truth is a term used in statistics and machine learning that means checking the results of machine learning for accuracy against the real world.\nThe term is borrowed from meteorology, where \"ground truth\" refers to information obtained on site.\nThe term implies a kind of reality check for machine learning algorithms.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Ground Truth mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In statistics and machine learning, overfitting occurs when a model tries to predict a trend in data that is too noisy.\nOverfitting is the result of an overly complex model with too many parameters.\nA model that is overfitted is inaccurate because the trend does not reflect the reality of the data.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Overfitting mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Disjunctive normal form (DNF) is the normalization of a logical formula in Boolean mathematics.\nIn other words, a logical formula is said to be in disjunctive normal form if it is a disjunction of conjunctions with every variable and its negation is present once in each conjunction.\nAll disjunctive normal forms are non-unique, as all disjunctive normal forms for the same proposition are mutually equivalent.\nDisjunctive normal form is widely used in areas such as automated theorem proving.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Disjunctive Normal Form (DNF) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A smart contract is a computer protocol that facilities the transfer of digital assets between parties under the agreed-upon stipulations or terms.\nIt is similar to a traditional contract in most ways including definition of rules and penalties around the agreement except for the fact that it can also enforce the agreed-upon obligations automatically.\nWith blockchain technologies and bitcoin adoption, smart contracts are becoming popular in usage.\nA smart contract is also known as a crypto contract.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Smart Contract mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A sparse array is an array of data in which many elements have a value of zero.\nThis is in contrast to a dense array, where most of the elements have non-zero values or are \u201cfull\u201d of numbers.\nA sparse array may be treated differently than a dense array in digital data handling.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Sparse Array mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A sparse matrix is a matrix in which many or most of the elements have a value of zero.\nThis is in contrast to a dense matrix, where many or most of the elements have a non-zero value.\nSparse matrices are used in specific ways in computer science, and have different data analysis and storage protocols and techniques related to their use.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Sparse Matrix mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Mixed reality is a type of hybrid system that involves both physical and virtual elements.\nMany experts describe mixed reality as the sliding scale between a fully physical environment with no virtual elements, and a completely virtual environment.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Mixed Reality mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A recursive descent parser is a type of parsing tool that works on a recursive basis, in other words, on the basis of using one instance of a command or event to generate another.\nRecursive descent parsers can be used to parse different types of code, such as XML, or other inputs.\nThey are a specific type of parsing technology that can involve nested or built-in subsequent operations.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Recursive Descent Parser mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A self-balancing binary search tree is a type of data structure that self-adjusts to provide consistent levels of node access.\nIn a self-balancing binary search tree, the connections from the top node to additional nodes are sorted and re-adjusted so that the tree is even, and search trajectory lines for each end node are equal in terms of length.\nA self-balancing binary search tree is also known as a balanced tree or height-balanced binary search tree.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Self-Balancing Binary Search Tree mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Discretization is the process of replacing a continuum with a finite set of points.\nIn the context of digital computing, discretization takes place when continuous-time signals, such as audio or video, are reduced to discrete signals.\nThe process of discretization is integral to analog-to-digital conversion.\nDiscretization is related to the term quantization.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Discretization mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Nonlinearity is a term best understood by the definition of its opposite.\nSomething that is linear can be expressed with a straight line.\nIn mathematics, linear equations have certain qualities that nonlinear equations do not have.\nIn the context of information technology, nonlinearity describes a system whose output does not vary in proportion to its input.\nNonlinear systems are more of a challenge to control.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Nonlinearity mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An infinite sequence is an endless progression of discrete objects, especially numbers.\nA sequence has a clear starting point and is written in a definite order.\nAn infinite sequence may include all the numbers of a particular set, such as all positive integers {1, 2, 3, 4 \u2026}.\nIt could also be an arithmetic sequence or a geometric sequence.\nAn infinite sequence was at the heart of the thought experiment called the Turing Machine.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Infinite Sequence mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Name resolution, in the context of programming, is the linking of identifiers within the programming environment to the actual program components that they represent.\nThese names may be stored in lookup tables or as part of a namespace hierarchy.\nThe purpose of the naming is to provide a shorthand reference to coded material.\nThe process may be used to call a function, variable or other component from a repository of named entities.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Name Resolution mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A lexeme is a sequence of alphanumeric characters in a token.\nThe term is used in both the study of language and in the lexical analysis of computer program compilation.\nIn the context of computer programming, lexemes are part of the input stream from which tokens are identified.\nAn invalid or illegal token produces an error.\nA lexeme is one of the building blocks of language.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Lexeme mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A machine cycle consists of the steps that a computer\u2019s processor executes whenever it receives a machine language instruction.\nIt is the most basic CPU operation, and modern CPUs are able to perform millions of machine cycles per second.\nThe cycle consists of three standard steps: fetch, decode and execute.\nIn some cases, store is also incorporated into the cycle.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Machine Cycle mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Ordinary least squares regression (OLSR) is a generalized linear modeling technique.\nIt is used for estimating all unknown parameters involved in a linear regression model, the goal of which is to minimize the sum of the squares of the difference of the observed variables and the explanatory variables.\nOrdinary least squares regression is also known as ordinary least squares or least squared errors regression.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Ordinary Least Squares Regression (OLSR) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Theoretical computer science is a term generally used to refer to parts of the computer science world that are less \u201chands-on\u201d or demonstrable and more theoretical in nature.\nIT professionals who discuss theoretical computer science are often talking about some of the more mathematical and esoteric ideas about computing, and some of the more theoretical applications of technologies like algorithms, data structures and cryptography.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Theoretical Computer Science mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Robotics is the industry related to the engineering, construction and operation of robots \u2013 a broad and diverse field related to many commercial industries and consumer uses.\nThe field of robotics generally involves looking at how any physical constructed technology system can perform a task or play a role in any interface or new technology.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Robotics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Online machine learning is a type of machine learning that utilizes dynamic inputs.\nIt takes data in real time and applies it to a machine learning algorithm.\nIt is called online machine learning because the program must be connected to some network that provides the dynamic input stream.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Online Machine Learning mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An evolutionary algorithm is considered a component of evolutionary computation in artificial intelligence.\nAn evolutionary algorithm functions through the selection process in which the least fit members of the population set are eliminated, whereas the fit members are allowed to survive and continue until better solutions are determined.\nIn other words, evolutionary algorithms are computer applications which mimic biological processes in order to solve complex problems.\nOver time, the successful members evolve to present the optimized solution to the problem.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Evolutionary Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Cognitive architecture is a hypothesis inspired by the human mind in which systems work together along with the necessary resources to attain intelligent behavior in any complex environment.\nCognitive architecture's aim is the development of artificial agents that support the same capabilities as that of the human mind.\nIn other words, it focuses on the tight integration between cognitive science and artificial intelligence.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Cognitive Architecture mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A random forest is a data construct applied to machine learning that develops large numbers of random decision trees analyzing sets of variables.\nThis type of algorithm helps to enhance the ways that technologies analyze complex data.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Random Forest mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Merkle tree is a specific type of data construct in which each non-leaf node of the tree contains hash values of its own child nodes.\nBecause a Merkle tree demonstrates effective hashing techniques, it is popular in many industries and is being used to help innovate in finance.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Merkle Tree mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Segregated Witness (SegWit) is a protocol that has been implemented in the bitcoin cybercurrency community.\nIt is characterized as a soft fork in the bitcoin chain, and has been widely accepted by bitcoin miners and users.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Segregated Witness (SegWit) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A user-activated soft fork (UASF) is a specific kind of divergence in a bitcoin or cryptocurrency chain.\nThe fork leads to a lack of consensus in nodes, which may be resolved at a later point.\nIt has interesting applications to the ongoing administration of a cryptocurrency model.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does User-Activated Soft Fork (UASF) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A hash list is simply a set of hash values related to sets of data items linked together in a file or folder system or some other connective array format.\nHash lists are used to analyze data in a database or other environment, to access one or more of these items, to assess the size of an array, or for other investigative purposes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hash List mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A hash chain is commonly defined as the repeated application of a cryptographic hash function to a given data asset.\nThis type of hash cryptography can be extremely useful in some specific security setups.\nBy providing a successive chain, hash chains make it harder for a snooping hacker to hijack a data asset through applying a single input.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Hash Chain mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Block size in bitcoin refers to the size of a block of code representing a recent chain of bitcoin transactions.\nAt a given point, a bitcoin block is added to other blocks to form a continuous chain, which facilitates the authentication of bitcoin transactions.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Block Size mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Game theory is the study of using mathematical models to assess interactive systems.\nMany experts describe it as the analysis of interplay between independent rational decision-makers or actors.\nGame theory is useful in many different kinds of research, such as projects that take into account elements of human psychology.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Game Theory mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Connectionism is a particular philosophy applied to artificial intelligence and other technology advances; it perceives the human mind as being linked to complex interconnected networks.\nMany attribute the term to Donald Hebbs, a data scientist active in the 1940s.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Connectionism mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In machine learning, feature selection is the use of specific variables or data points to maximize efficiency in this type of advanced data science.\nFeature selection is also known as variable selection, attribute selection or subset selection.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Feature Selection mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computational mathematics involves areas of mathematical work that focus on the application of math to computing technologies.\nBecause so much of the programming and hardware world depends on mathematical operations, there are seemingly infinite ways to apply computational mathematics to computer science.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computational Mathematics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An inference engine is a tool used to make logical deductions about knowledge assets.\nExperts often talk about the inference engine as a component of a knowledge base.\nInference engines are useful in working with all sorts of information, for example, to enhance business intelligence.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Inference Engine mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Computational neuroscience is the science of studying brain function with computer science modeling, and looking at all of the activity of the human brain through the lens of computer science.\nScientists engaged in computational neuroscience might build models to understand how neurons, axons and dendrites work.\nThe field of computational neuroscience blends aspects of computer science and electrical engineering with traditional studies of biology.\nComputational neuroscience is also known as theoretical neuroscience.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Computational Neuroscience mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Mycin project was a computer program used to diagnose infections and figure out which types of bacteria were causing them in patients.\nThe system was actually not used in clinical practice, but it constitutes an excellent early example of a digital expert system and a precursor to much more sophisticated machine learning and knowledge base systems years later.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Mycin mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Simulated annealing is a mathematical and modeling method that is often used to help find a global optimization in a particular function or problem.\nSimulated annealing gets its name from the process of slowly cooling metal, applying this idea to the data domain.\nSimulated annealing is also known simply as annealing.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Simulated Annealing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The MIT Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Lab (CSAIL) is an office dedicated to researching new artificial intelligence trends and other technological advancements to determine how computing will change over the next half-century.\nThe project comes out of two individual MIT projects: its Laboratory for Computer Science, founded in 1963, and its Artificial Intelligence Laboratory, founded in 1959.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does MIT Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A fractal dimension is a ratio for figuring out the complexity of a system given its measurement.\nFractal dimensions can be useful in machine learning (ML) as part of dimensionality reduction, in order to change how machine learning systems deal with data.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Fractal Dimension mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Inductive reasoning is the use of evidence to propose a theory, or in other words, assuming a given outcome from past outcomes or other available data.\nInductive reasoning is probabilistic or uncertain in the sense that it relies on the given data instead of other types of discovery.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Inductive Reasoning mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A sorting algorithm is an algorithm that sorts arrays of data.\nDifferent types of sort algorithms include:Comparison sortsMerge sortsInsertions sortsBubble sortsQuick sorts","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Sorting Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A RESTful API is an API that conforms to the representational state transfer or REST model.\nRESTful APIs are sometimes easier for developers to use because they have a familiar syntax and set of protocols.\nAs more functionality has been built into the internet, developers have talked a lot about the benefits of RESTful architecture.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does RESTful API mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The random walk is a somewhat popular mathematical construct that is used in computer science, and now in machine learning.\nIt is described as a \"stochastic\" process because it works through the application of random variables.\nThe random walk essentially tracks incremental steps by a particular modeled intelligence or digital \"rational actor.\n\"","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Random Walk mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Apriori algorithm is an algorithm that attempts to operate on database records, particularly transactional records, or records including certain numbers of fields or items.\nIt is one of a number of algorithms using a \"bottom-up approach\" to incrementally contrast complex records, and it is useful in today's complex machine learning and artificial intelligence projects.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Apriori Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "AdaBoost is a type of algorithm that uses an ensemble learning approach to weight various inputs.\nIt was designed by Yoav Freund and Robert Schapire in the early 21st century.\nIt has now become somewhat of a go-to method for different kinds of boosting in machine learning paradigms.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does AdaBoost mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In the context of computer science and digital communications, \"piggybacking\" refers to a situation where an unauthorized party gains access to some system in connection with an authorized party.\nThis can happen in several ways, including piggybacking on public wireless networks, and piggybacking into a password-protected system.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Piggybacking mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Particle swarm optimization (PSO) is a population-based stochastic method that helps with optimization problems.\nIt is modeled after natural processes, such as the flocking of birds or the movement of schools of fish.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Particle Swarm Optimization (PSO) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The input layer of a neural network is composed of artificial input neurons, and brings the initial data into the system for further processing by subsequent layers of artificial neurons.\nThe input layer is the very beginning of the workflow for the artificial neural network.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Input Layer mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A restricted Boltzmann machine (RBM) is a type of artificial neural network invented by Geoff Hinton, a pioneer in machine learning and neural network design.\nThis type of generative network is useful for filtering, feature learning and classification, and it employs some types of dimensionality reduction to help tackle complicated inputs.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Restricted Boltzmann Machine (RBM) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An activation function is the function in an artificial neuron that delivers an output based on inputs.\nActivation functions in artificial neurons are an important part of the role that the artificial neurons play in modern artificial neural networks.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Activation Function mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The gradient descent algorithm is a strategy that helps to refine machine learning operations.\nThe gradient descent algorithm works toward adjusting the input weights of neurons in artificial neural networks and finding local minima or global minima in order to optimize a problem.\nThe gradient descent algorithm is also known simply as gradient descent.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Gradient Descent Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The feedforward neural network is a specific type of early artificial neural network known for its simplicity of design.\nThe feedforward neural network has an input layer, hidden layers and an output layer.\nInformation always travels in one direction \u2013 from the input layer to the output layer \u2013 and never goes backward.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Feedforward Neural Network mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Competitive learning is a type of unsupervised learning model used in machine learning and artificial intelligence systems.\nSome of the interesting new formats of machine learning projects are partially based on competitive learning include self-organizing component neural networks.\nThat makes this an integral idea in the machine learning community.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Competitive Learning mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A learning algorithm is an algorithm used in machine learning to help the technology to imitate the human learning process.\nCombined with technologies like neural networks, learning algorithms create involved, sophisticated learning programs.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Learning Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An array data structure is a fundamental element of computer programming that creates collections of individual elements, each of which has its own array index or key.\nArrays are handy ways to store various bits of group information in nearly any common programming language.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Array Data Structure mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Edge detection is a process applied to digital image processing.\nIt is really a name for a collection of algorithms and tools that do a particular thing \u2013 enhancing the edges of objects in an image by using mathematical models.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Edge Detection mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Bayesian statistics is a type of dynamic probability statistics commonly used in today\u2019s world of artificial intelligence and machine learning.\nThese technologies seek to go beyond pure linear programming to a more probabilistic approach.\nBayesian statistics complements this idea, because a Bayesian statistical approach is more sophisticated and based on a different probabilistic foundation than \u201cfrequentist\u201d statistics that have been the most common type of statistical analysis done to date.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Bayesian Statistics mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Tree traversal is a process in the use of tree models that evaluates the nodes of a tree on a systematic basis.\nVarious types of tree traversal including depth-first and breadth-first traversal models help engineers, data scientists and others to understand the contents of a tree structure.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Tree Traversal mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In computer science, the theory of computation provides a sort of \u201cunified field theory\u201d of how computers work.\nIt uses the elements of automatic theory, computability theory and computational complexity theory to understand the nature of computing problems and how computing operations are performed.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Theory of Computation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Multidimensional Expressions (MDX) is a query language for handling multidimensional data.\nMicrosoft uses this language to work with these types of data sets in server analysis.\nMultidimensional data is created when the contents of a data set exceed two dimensions, and when traditional Structured Query Language (SQL) no longer serves as a sufficient extractor.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Multidimensional Expressions (MDX) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Magnetomotive force (MMF) is a component or part of the equation of magnetic flux in magnetic circuits.\nAs an analogy to electromotive force, MMF \u201cdrives\u201d magnetic flux through a magnetic circuit.\nMagnetomotive force is also known as magnetic potential.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Magnetomotive Force (MMF) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Quantum as a service (QaaS) is a term for services that bring the functionality of quantum computing to clients through cloud delivery processes.\nThis is part of a range of services based on the broader software as a service (SaaS) model.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Quantum as a Service (QaaS) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A deterministic algorithm is an algorithm that is purely determined by its inputs, where no randomness is involved in the model.\nDeterministic algorithms will always come up with the same result given the same inputs.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Deterministic Algorithm mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A deterministic automaton is a computer science concept where transition results are determined by the input, and no random arbitration occurs.\nIn a deterministic automaton, there are a set of states, a set of inputs, and a function that brings the result to the next state.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Deterministic Automaton mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A deterministic finite automaton is a type of deterministic algorithm based on a state that changes with inputs.\nThese are also known as deterministic finite state machines or deterministic finite acceptors.\nThey are different from probabilistic and non-deterministic models in that one input (X) results in one known output (Y).\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Deterministic Finite Automaton (DFA) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Scunthorpe problem is a relatively common technology issue where systems censor data based on faulty or irrelevant designations.\nIt's named after the town of Scunthorpe in North Lincolnshire, England.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Scunthorpe Problem mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Parallel functional programming refers to a specific philosophy of computer science that uses functional programming in conjunction with parallelism to work with declarative programming in specific ways.\nBy utilizing functional programming this way, developer teams are able to introduce specific operations on interdependent tasks and transformational systems based on parallel algorithms.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Parallel Functional Programming mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Non-deterministic polynomial time (NP) is actually a marker used to point to a set of problems and bounds of the capability of certain types of computing.\nNP refers to the set of problems that can be solved in polynomial time by a non-deterministic Turing machine.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Non-Deterministic Polynomial Time (NP) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A deterministic system is a system in which a given initial state or condition will always produce the same results.\nThere is no randomness or variation in the ways that inputs get delivered as outputs.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Deterministic System mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A non-deterministic Turing machine is a theoretical type of computer in which specific commands may allow for a range of actions, rather than a specific command leading to only one allowable action in the deterministic model of computing.\nWhere deterministic programming is a simple condition of \u2018input X leads to action Y\u2019, a non-deterministic Turing machine setup would theoretically allow for input X to lead to a variety of actions Y(array).\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Non-Deterministic Turing Machine (NTM) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A Markov decision process (MDP) is something that professionals refer to as a \u201cdiscrete time stochastic control process.\n\u201d It's based on mathematics pioneered by Russian academic Andrey Markov in the late 19th and early 20th centuries.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Markov Decision Process (MDP) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Deep Q Networks (DQN) are neural networks (and/or related tools) that utilize deep Q learning in order to provide models such as the simulation of intelligent video game play.\nRather than being a specific name for a specific neural network build, Deep Q Networks may be composed of convolutional neural networks and other structures that use specific methods to learn about various processes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Deep Q-Networks mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Quantum decoherence in physics and quantum computing is the loss of quantum coherence.\nQuantum coherence is the idea that an individual particle or object has wave functions that can be split into two separate waves.\nWhen the waves operate together in a coherent way, that's referred to as quantum coherence.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Quantum Decoherence mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The term \u2018quantum coherence\u2019 represents the idea of a superpositioning that is at the heart of quantum mechanics and quantum computing.\nSpecifically, quantum coherence contemplates a situation where an object\u2019s wave property is split in two, and the two waves coherently interfere with each other.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Quantum Coherence mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "An exit code or exit status is a number that is returned by an executable to show whether it was successful.\nThis is also sometimes called a return code, or in some cases, an error code, although the terminology here may be slightly different.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Exit Code mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Function approximation is the study of selecting functions in a class that match target functions.\nIt\u2019s a process that is useful in applied mathematics and computer science.\nFunction approximation is often related to a Markov decision process (MDP) which consists of an agent and various states.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Function Approximation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Linear compatibility functions can be part of structured prediction work, where a machine learning program (or similar technology) attempts to solve for an identity in a classification problem by examining training inputs.\nThis sort of construct makes sense within the general framework of the neural network model that is innovating artificial intelligence at a fast clip.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Linear Compatibility Functions mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Structured prediction is a particular discipline applied to machine learning in which machine learning techniques predict structured objects.\nTypically, the structured prediction makes use of supervised machine learning programs with labels that can apply in order to produce outcomes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Structured Prediction mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A machine learning engineer is a particular type of data scientist who is profoundly involved in assessing and designing machine learning systems.\nThe machine learning engineer has a \"front row seat\" to the development of these new types of resources in the artificial intelligence field.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Machine Learning Engineer (MLE) mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Neurotechnology as a new prominent tech term describes any technology that helps us to understand brain function, or enables a direct connection of technology with the human nervous system.\nSince the technology world has made rapid advances in both observational technology for the human brain and cognitive modeling technology in artificial intelligence, there's a grey area in terms of what constitutes neurotechnology.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Neurotechnology mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Elixir is a programming language that runs on an Erlang virtual machine environment and helps to scale applications.\nAs a dynamic functional language utilizing a VM model, Elixir is described as a scripting language that's an alternative to using only JavaScript and Python or other interpreted languages for just-in-time compiling.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Elixir mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Linear multiclass classification is a specific kind of targeted algorithm philosophy in machine learning and the field of structured prediction that uses both linear and multiclass methods.\nA multiclass classification is used to classify more than two classes \u2013 in contrast to a binary classification.\nA linear classification uses an object\u2019s characteristics to classify it by basing a decision on the value of a linear combination of characteristics.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Linear Multiclass Classification mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "True positives as results in machine learning classification problems involve outputs where a test observes a positive, where a positive was also predicted.\nThis is part of the classical confusion matrix that engineers use as a model for discussing a classifying algorithm.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does True Positives mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The B programming language is a language based on Basic Combined Programming Language or BCPL and a precursor to the C programming language (and subsequent C suite languages) that is so ubiquitous in codebase programming over the past few decades.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does B Programming Language mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "In reinforcement learning, a reward path is a path that an agent takes in order to obtain cumulative rewards.\nThis terminology isn't really used very much on its own in machine learning, but the concept of reward is central to many machine learning algorithms and Markov decision process models.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Reward Path mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The Swift programming language is a language that Apple developed for various operating systems, including some of its smartphone operating systems, as well as desktop platforms.\nIt's a take on Objective-C that similarly utilizes variables to store values.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Swift mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "The phrase chatOps is used to talk about new platforms and technologies that connect work and the people that work on projects through chat interactivity.\nIt's a somewhat unique and new take on the idea of digital chat technology where messaging apps have allowed us to bridge various communication barriers in unprecedented ways.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": " Definition - What does ChatOps mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Logic programming is a type of computer programming that is based on formal logic rules.\nIn a sense, logic programming corresponds to the use of mathematical equations and other logical constructs to drive programming outcomes.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Logic Programming mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Layer-wise relevance propagation is a method for understanding deep neural networks that uses a particular design path to observe how the individual layers of the program work.\nThese types of techniques help engineers to learn more about how neural networks do what they do, and they are crucial in combating the problem of \"black box operation\" in artificial intelligence, where technologies become so powerful and complex that it's hard for humans to understand how they produce results.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": " Definition - What does Layer-Wise Relevance Propagation mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Neuralink is an American company using neurotechnology to research the possibility of future innovations in high-tech neurology applications.\nNeuralink has gained visibility as a project backed by Elon Musk, and as a ground-breaking way of looking at neurotech in general.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Neuralink mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Neuroimaging is defined as the use of \"techniques to either directly or indirectly image the structure, function or pharmacology of the nervous system.\n\" It\u2019s a general way to advance neuroscience through principles of observation and direct application.\nIt comes in many forms, from digital neural networks to direct mechanical interactive technologies.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Neuroimaging mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A decision scientist is a technology professional who is mainly focused on making technologies work for decision-making and enterprise.\nHowever, the term \"decision scientist\" is really meaningful when you contrast it with another similar job role referred to as a \"data scientist\" or \"big data scientist.\n\"","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Decision Scientist mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A control structure is a codebase portion that supports decisions based on analysis of variables.\nThese functional components are eminently useful in computer science and computer programming.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Control Structure mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "A system is said to be \"Turing complete\" in computer theory if it can be used to emulate a Turing machine, which is a theoretical construct designed by mid-century mathematician and computer scientist Alan Turing.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Turing Complete mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Concurrent computing describes a process where multiple programs or threads are managed by one computing system through the process of alternating timeshared slices.\nIn many of these systems, it can appear that processes are being executed in parallel, but concurrent processes are little bit different than parallel computing.\n","created": "Sun, 24 May 2020 16:09:03 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": "Definition - What does Concurrent Computing mean?","tags": ["english definitions"],"version": 1},{"_id": "","answer": "Bidirectional search is a type of search and sort activity that combines two directional approaches, so that the generator in question searches in two directions at the same time.\nUsing this method can decrease the amount of search activity needed to achieve a particular result.\n","created": "Thu, 21 May 2020 18:46:00 GMT","createdSemester": "SS 20","created_by": "schneiderpa77403@th-nuernberg.de","latest": "true","question": " Definition - What does Bidirectional Search mean?","tags": ["Englisch"],"version": 1}]}